Open your eyes.
.شماتو باز كن
Why tell me that dream?
را اون رويا رو به من ميي؟
You said I could tellyou whatever I wanted.
خودت فتي هر ي بخوام .ميتونم بهت بم
All right. Anything else you should tell me before we start?
خيله خُب. يز ديه اي مونده كه قبل از شروع بخواي بهم بي؟
Nothingyou don 't know. I was about to turn 25.
يزي نيست كه ندوني .داشتم 25 ساله ميشدم
I liked eating, sleeping, making love, like everyone.
، عاشق خوردن، خوابيدن .عشق بازي كردن، مثل همه آدما بودم
Andyou know what everyone does when they get up.
خودت ميدوني وقتي همه از .خواب بيدار ميشن يكار ميكنن
OPE N Y OU R EYES
شمهايت را باز كن (شماتو باز كن)
Where are you going?
كجا داري ميري؟
Out.
.بيرون
Stop leaving messages on the alarm.
.ديه برام روي ساعت يام نزار
Why?
را؟
Just don't.
.يام نزار ديه
Because it pisses me off.
.ون عصابمو ريده مالي ميكنه
Come on, for fuck's sake.
.زود باش ديه، لعنتي
- I'll slaughteryou. - We'll see about that.
.دخلتو ميارم - .خواهيم ديد -
You've got three cars. Why do we always go in this wreck?
تو سه تا ماشين داري را بايد هميشه سوار اين قراضه بشيم؟
Come on. I'm in a hurry.
.بجنب. عجله دارم
Are you backing out? I missed class for this.
خودتو ميزني به اون راه؟ .به خاطر اين به كلاسم نرسيدم
I'm seeing my partners after. Why do you think I'm dressed up?
با شركام  قرار دارم را فكر ميكني من خوشتي كردم؟
So you can shout at them. You like that.
تا بتوني سرشون داد بزني .از اين كار خوشت مياد
I don't shout.
.من داد نمي زنم
- So tell me, did you screw her? - Screw who?
راستي بو، باهاش عشق و حال كردي؟ - كيو ميي؟ -
Whoever was there when I rang last night.
هموني كه ديشب وقتي زن .زدم اونجا بود
I was alone last night. Anyway, what is it to you?
ديشب تنها بودم بذريم، به تو ه ربطي داره آخه؟
Nothing. You can do what you want with your life.
هيي. هر كاري دوست داري .ميتوني با زنديت بكني
Thanks very much.
.خيلي ممنون
Let's change the subject.
.بهتره بحث رو عوض كنيم
- Did you screw her? - Give me a break. I was on my own.
با دختره بُکن بُکن داشتي؟ - .بزار نفس بكشم. من تنها بودم -
So, you did. Was it the one you talk so much about?
س خوابونديش و حال کردي. هموني نبود كه دربارش خيلي حرف ميزدي؟
- Who? - That Nuria.
كي؟ - .همون نوريا -
My God, I can't believe it!
!خداي من، باورم نميشه
Cesar seeing the same woman twice!
!سِزار با زنـه دوبار خوابيده
- She must be great in bed. - She isn't bad.
بايد تو رختخواب كارش خيلي عالي باشه - .بد نيست -
Bastard! When are you going to tell me the secret?
عوضي! كي ميخواي اون راز رو بهم بي؟
- What secret? - The recipe for Coca-Cola.
كدوم راز؟ - .دستور ساخت كوكا كولا -
- Look, the kind you like. - Yeah. Change the--
.ببين، همونيه كه دوست داري - .آره. خودتي ميزني به كوه علي  -
What did you eat today?
امروز ي خوردي؟
Nothing. That's my problem. I'm starved!
هيي. مشكلم همينه !دارم از شني ميميرم
It's funny when you ask them what they value most in a man.
خندت مييره وقتي از زنا ميرسي .از ي مردا بيشتر خوششون مياد
"I like him to be intelligent, to be honest, to be kind."
دوست دارم باهوش باشند" ".صادق باشند، مهربون باشند
It's all shit! You'd have problems ifyou were like me.
همش مزخرفه! اه مثه من باشي .دار دردسر ميشي
Not that again! You aren't ugly.
!باز شروع نكن .تو زشت نيستي
Anybody would like to have your face. You're normal.
همه دوست دارن قيافه ي تو .رو داشته باشند. قيافت عاديه
- Normal. That doesn't mean handsome. - You're handsome.
.عادي. اين معنيش خوشل نيست - .تو خوشلي -
I'm acceptable, when you're not beside me.
وقتي كنار تو باشم .همه منو قبول ميكنند
You're like anorexics. They insist they're fat, and end up crazy.
مثه كسايي هستي كه مرض اشتها دارند .اصرار دارن كه اقن، آخرشم ديوونه ميشن
When some girl ties you down, the rest of us will get a chance.
وقتي يه دختري باهات رابطه برقرار ميكنه .بقيه ي ما يه شانس يرمون مياد
- Yeah, yeah. - Why not?
.آره، تو راست ميي - را كه نه؟ -
Ifyou meet the right girl--
.اه  دختر روياهات رو ببيني
She doesn't exist.
.نين دختري وجود نداره
Shit!
!لعنتي
- How did I miss that? - God punished you.
را اين توو خراب كردم؟ - .خدا مجازاتت كرد -
You're for it.
.خودت خواستي
- Who are you saying that to? - To God.
اينو به كي ميي؟ - .خدا -
Do you believe in God?
به خدا اعتقاد داري؟
- Don't start all that shit. - Ijust asked a question.
.اين مزخرفاتو شروع نكن - .فقط يه سوال رسيدم -
Ifyou don't want to, don't answer.
.اه دوست نداري، جواب نده
I don't believe in God.
.به خدا اعتقاد ندارم
How do you explain what happened?
اتفاقي رو كه افتاد طوري توضيح ميدي؟
- How do you mean? - Your face.
منظورت يه؟ - .صورتت -
- There is no explanation. - I believe there is.
.توضيحي وجود نداره - .من فكر ميكنم وجود داره -
- You believe I'm mad. - I only believe what I see.
.تو فكر ميكني من ديوونم - .من فقط به يزي كه ميبينم باور دارم -
You haven't let me see your face yet.
.هنوز نذاشتي من هره ت رو ببينم
And I won't.
.نخواهمم  ذاشت
Do you really think you're a monster, Cesar?
واقعا فكر ميكني يه هيولايي، سزار؟
- Come on, let me see. - Stickyour hand up your ass!
.يالا، بزار صورتتو ببينم - !دستتو بکن تو سوراخ کون ت  - (دستتو به من نزن)
Take it easy, brat! I'm sick of all your stories.
!آروم باش، بد اخلاق .داستانات حالمو به هم ميزنه
- Leave me alone! - I'll kick the shit out ofyou!
!تنهام بزاريد - .بالاخره به حرفت ميارم -
I can't work with you in here. Leave us on our own.
، تا وقتي اينجايي نمي تونم كارمو بكنم .تنهامون بزاريد
On my responsibility.
.مسئوليتش با من
You're just a spoiled brat who--
...تو فقط يه به ي لوس و نُنُري
My parents are dead, asshole!
!در و مادرم مُردند، کونـخَرنه
You made up a story so as not to admit what you did.
از خودت يه داستان ساختي تا .كاريو كه كردي منكر بشي
Is that true?
حقيقت داره؟
What?
ي؟
That you're a spoiled brat.
.كه يه به ي لوس و ننري
My father had a restaurant chain. That's not my fault.
درم رستوران زنجيره اي داشت .اين كه تقصير من نيست
When did your parents die?
در و مادرت كي مردند؟
Fifteen years ago, in an accident.
.انزده سال يش، تو يه تصادف
- And now you're rich. - So they say.
.و حالا تو ثروتـمندي - .اينطوري مين -
Then why don't you want a lawyer?
س را يه وكيل نميخواي؟
They say they can get me the best.
اونا مين ميتونن برام .بهترين وكيلو بيرن
- But they want me stuck here forever. - Who are they?
.ولي ميخوان من تا ابد اينجا بوسم - اونا كين؟ -
My partners. They've been sucking my blood since I was a kid.
شركام. از وقتي به بودم .داشتند خونمو مي مكيدند
Now they've got everything. They've cut me out.
حالا كه همه ي دارند .منو انداختن زندان
It wasn't them. It was me.
كار اونا نبود .من اينكارو كردم
I don't care.
.برام مهم نيست
Let's see, Cesar. Do you know why you're here?
ببينم، سزار ميدوني را اينجايي؟
- Because I wear a mask, I guess. - No.
.فكر كنم ون نقاب ميزنم - .نه -
Because you killed someone.
.ون يكي رو كشتي
Or don't you remember?
يادت نمياد؟
- Tell me, don't you remember? - Fuck! Stop it!
بهم بو، يادت نمياد؟ - !اييدمت! تمومش كن ديه -
We must get things clear ifyou want us to get on.
اه ميخواي راحت شي بايد .همه ي رو برامون بي
I don't want us to get on!
!نمي خوام راحت شم
Is your solution to sit in this hole and not talk?
راه حلت اينه كه تو اين سلول بشيني و حرف نزني؟
- Aren't we talking now? - After two months.
الان با هم حرف نمي زنيم؟ - .بعد دو ماه -
I've been trying for two months.
.دو ماه داشتم سعي ميكردم
- Read the reports. - I've read them.
.زارشا رو بخون - .خوندمشون -
I want you to tell me, if possible, sitting on a chair.
ازت ميخوام اه امكان داره .رو صندلي بشيني و خودت بهم بي
Or are you going to stay there?
يا ميخواي همونجا بموني؟
I like the floor.
.رو زمين راحتم
It's the only thing that seems real.
اين تنها يزيه كه .واقعي بنظر مياد
What does everything else seem?
بقيه ي يزا ه جوري بنظر ميرسند؟
Everything else is a lie.
.يزاي ديه همشون دروغه
All this seems a lie, including you.
.اينا همشون به انضمام تو، دروغه
You don't even wear a white coat.
.تو حتي رووش سفيد نوشيدي
- Do you think I should? - Doctors wear them.
فكر ميكني بايد بوشم؟ - .زشکا مي وشن -
I took it off so you'd forget I was a doctor.
من درش آوردم تا تو فراموش .كني من دكترم
So that you'd like me more.
.تا بيشتر منو دوست داشته باشي
It didn't work. I hate the sight ofyou.
فايده اي نداشت .از قيافت بدم مياد
Now that we're friends--
.حالا كه با هم دوست شديم
- I've got no friends. - Tell me what happened.
.من هي دوستي ندارم - .بهم بو ه اتفاقي افتاد -
The sooneryou talk, the sooner I'll go.
هر ه زودتر حرف بزني .من زودتر ميرم
Hey! Happy birthday and all the things people usually say.
هي! تولدت مبارك و هر ي كه .مردم معمولا مين
Thankyou, thankyou.
.مُكرم، مكرم
- Where did you find her? - In the library.
از كجا يداش كردي؟ - .تو كتابخونه -
- She tried to steal my book. - It was mine.
.ميخواست كتابمو بدزده - .كتاب خودم بود -
- Anyway, Cesar, Sofia. - Hello.
.به هر حال، سزار، سوفيا - .سلام -
Happy birthday.
.تولدت مبارك
- Thankyou. - Your present.
.مکرم - .هديه ت -
- Thanks a lot. - We bought it between us.
.خيلي ممنون - .شريكي خريديم -
Then I have to thank both ofyou.
.س بايد از هر دوتون تشكر كنم
Stop chatting her up and open it.
اينقدر حرف نزن .بازش كن
- I'd rather open them tomorrow. - Whatever.
.ترجيح ميدم فردا باز كنم - .هر جور راحتي -
- Like a drink? - Sure.
نوشيدني ميخواي؟ - .آره -
I'll leave this upstairs.
.اينو ميزارم طبقه ي بالا
Hello.
.سلام
- What are you doing here? - Happy birthday, darling.
اينجا يكار ميكني؟ - .تولدت مبارك، عزيزم -
Thankyou.
.ممنون
But I didn't askyou to the party.
.ولي تو رو به جشن دعوت نكرده بودم
That was nice ofyou.
.اين نظر لطفت بود
I brought you a present, too. Why not open it?
منم برات يه كادو آوردم را بازش نمي كني؟
No, thanks. I already know what's inside.
.نه، ممنون. ميدونم ي داخلشه
- And last night? - Listen, Nuria.
و ديشب؟ - .وش كن، نوريا -
I don't like you just turning up, much less coming into my room.
دوست ندارم بياي اين بالا .تو اتاق من
- Well! Do I have to apologize? - No.
خُب!!! بايد عذر خواهي كنم؟ - .نه -
You have to go.
.بايد بري
Right. I know what it is.
.باشه. ميدونم جريان يه
You don't want to be seen twice with the same girl.
نميخواي با يه دختر دوبار .ديده بشي
It would ruin your reputation.
.به شهرتت لطمه ميزنه
- You got it in one. - And there's someone else.
.درست فهميدي - .اي يكي ديه در ميونه -
- Right? - Who?
درسته؟ - كي رو ميي؟ -
The brunette you were talking to a minute ago?
همون مو مشكيه كه يه دقيقه قبل داشتي باهاش حرف ميزدي؟
Well, she's not bad.
.خب، اونم بدک نيست
I don't care.
.برام مهم نيست
I don't need to be seen with you.
.نيازي ندارم با تو ديده بشم
Hold me.
.منو بير
Come on.
!يالا
A little kiss.
.يه بوس كوولو
Until when? Until next Friday?
تا كي؟ جمعه ي بعدي؟
Can you manage a weekend without me?
ميتوني يه آخر هفته رو بدون من سر كني؟
Excuse me. I must see to my guests.
.معذرت ميخوام.بايد به مهمونام برسم
Yes, the brunette will take time. She looks that type.
آره، رفتن رو مخ مو مشكيه وقت ميبره .بنظر از اون مورده
- That type? - Yes.
اون مورد؟ - .آره -
The kind who can't find your zipper.
موردي كه نميتونه زي لباستو .يدا كنه
- Hello.
.سلام -
- What did you want? - To open this.
ميخواستي يكار كني؟ - .در اينو باز كنم -
Wait.
.صبر كن
I'll serve you.
.من برات ميريزم
Since when are you the waiter?
از كي تا حالا يشخدمت شدي؟
Don't you know I'm in catering?
نمي دوني من تو كار رستورانم؟
Are you all right?
حالت خوبه؟
- Can't you tell I'm elbowing in? - A bit.
نميتوني بي دارم درشو باز ميكنم؟ - .يه خرده -
I've got a slight problem.
.يه مشكل كويك دارم
- A girl's chasing me. - You don't say.
.يه دختره دنبالمه - .نو بابا -
- I need help to get rid ofher. - And I'm that help.
.براي خلاص شدن از شرش كمك ميخوام - .و اون كمك منم -
Shit! There she is!
!لعنتي! اوناهاش
- Where? - Don't look. Look over here.
كجا؟ - .ناه نكن. اينجا رو ناه كن -
That's it. Yes.
.خودشه.آره
Yes, yes, yes.
.آره، آره، آره
- Here we are.
.بفرما -
Well, act as ifwe were talking about something real interesting.
وانمود كن داريم درباره ي يه .موضوع خيلي جالب حرف ميزنيم
Nod your head, agree, say yes.
سرتو تكون بده، موافقت كن .بو آره
You know.
.ميدوني
- What a nice conversation. - Yes.
.ه فتوي قشني - .آره -
- And she's coming this way. - Fuck!
.و اون داره مياد اينطرف - !اوخ بِاه رفتم -
- What are you doing? - Don't worry, I'll guide you.
داري يكار ميكني؟ - .نران نباش، راهو نشونت ميدم -
- Straight on. - I don't see her.
.يه راست برو - .نمي بينمش -
Here it is. Go right in.
.همينجاست .بيا داخل
- I'm not going in there. - Well, I am. So long.
.من نميام اونجا - .خب، من ميرم.بدرود -
- He's in here. - You--
.اون اينجاست - .تو -
Well, we're safe.
.خب، جامون امنه
But we've got nothing to drink here.
.ولي اينجا نوشيدني نداريم
I think all you really want is to chat with me.
من فكر ميكنم تنها يزي كه تو .ميخواي اينه كه با من حرف بزني
Yes, that too. First, I want to save my skin.
آره، اينم درسته .اول، ميخوام خودمو نجات بدم
Can't you say you aren't interested?
نمي توني بي بهش علاقه نداري؟
She wouldn't care. She never gets tired.
.براش مهم نيست .اصلا خسته نميشه
- She must be feeling bad. - Yeah.
.اون بايد احساس بدي داشته باشه - .آره -
Of course.
.البته
So you're studying drama, like Pelayo?
س تو هم مثه لايو، هنر ميخوني؟
- For now. - Scenography?
.در حال حاضر - نقاشي؟ -
- Acting. - Really? To be an actress?
.بازيري - جدي؟ ميخواي بازير بشي؟ -
I am an actress. Is that a problem?
من يه بازيرم ايرادي داره؟
Yes. Aren't you ashamed?
آره. خجالت نمي كشي؟
Ashamed? Why should I be ashamed?
خجالت؟ را بايد خجالت بكشم؟
Actors aren't honest.
.بازيرا صادق نيستند
You're able to show emotions you don't have...
ميتوني احساساتي رو نشون .بدي كه اصلا نداري
or which, at most, you invent.
.يا حداقل از خودت در بياري
Right now you could be thinking...
همين الان ميتوني به .اين فكر كني كه
"This guy is a real drag. How can I dump him? "
اين يارو ه آدم يريه" "طوري بيونمش؟
- Really? - "And in catering. A pain in the ass."
راستي؟ - "و تو يشخدمتي. يه تيکه نقاشي روي کون " - (افتضاحه و مزخرفه)
But you're a good actress. It doesn't show.
ولي تو بازير خوبي هستي .اصلا نشون نميدي
- Hey, Pelayo! - I caught you.
!هي، لايو - .متون رو رفتم -
- Come in. - How's it going?
.بيا تو - اوضاعت طوره؟ -
Great. I'm a bit out of it now.
.عاليه. يه خرده زياده روي كردم
Drunk, you mean.
.منظورت اينه كه مستي
Why are you in here?
را شما اينجاييد؟
Sofia was protecting me from a female psychopath out there.
سوفيا داشت منو از يك بيمار زن .رواني كه اون بيرونه محافظت ميكرد
- She seemed dangerous. - Yeah.
.بنظر خطرناك ميومد - .آره -
- What about you? - I was drinking. Women don't chase me.
تو ي؟ - .من شراب ميخوردم.زنا دنبال من نميان -
- We're out of drink. - Here.
.ما مشروب نداريم - .بيا -
- Shit. - I'll get some more.
!لعنتي - .من ميرم كمي نوشيدني بيارم -
For all of us.
.براي هممون
Well, I guess I'll be going.
.خب، فكر كنم بهتره برم
- Why? - I'm drunk and don't feel well.
را؟ - .مستم و احساس خوبي ندارم -
Don't be stupid. It's just starting.
احمق نشو .تازه اول جشنه
- Foryou, it is. - Pelayo, you can't go.
.براي تو، آره - .لايو، تو نميتوني بري -
You're my guest ofhonor.
.تو مهمان افتخاري مني
You're a son of a bitch, Cesar.
.تو يه حرومزاده اي، سزار
- Why'd you say that? - The party's full of girls.
را اينو ميي؟ - .جشن ر از دختره -
I go for a piss, you start talking to her, and--
من رفتم دستشويي، تو ...باهاش حرف ميزني... و
What?
و ي؟
Nothing. And I look like an asshole.
.هيي. من مثه يه عوضيم
Tell me what's wrong.
.بو ي شده
- Why do you have to chat up Sofia? - No one's chatting up Sofia.
را تو بايد با سوفيا لاس بزني؟ - .هيكي با سوفيا لاس نميزد -
Yeah, and I'm blind, right?
آره، من كورم، درسته؟
You're certainly drunk.
.تو مطمئنا مستي
I'm drunk, but I'll tell you this.
من مستم .ولي اينو بهت ميم
I like Sofia a hell of a lot.
.من سوفيا رو خيلي دوست دارم
She may even be the girl of my dreams.
.شايد اون حتي دختر روياهام باشه
But if she fucks up our friendship, she can go to hell.
ولي اه اون بِرينه به دوستيمون .ميتونه بره به دَرک
I feel the same.
.منم همين احساسو دارم
Sure.
.حتما
Pelayo, where are you going?
لايو، كجا ميري؟
- Home. - Already?
.خونه - به اين زودي؟ -
- Yeah, I'm wrecked. - I'll come with you.
.آره، داغونم - .منم باهات ميام -
Don't bother. You stay.
.خودتو اذيت نكن. بمون
Are you going, too?
تو هم داري ميري؟
I have to get up early.
.باد صبح زود بيدار شم
I can run you home later.
.ميتونم بعدا برسونمت خونه
Stay on. I'm leaving you in good hands.
.بمون. يش خوب كسي ميزارمت
What's wrong with him?
اون شه؟
He's drunk.
.مسته
- Is he annoyed with us? - No.
از دست ما ناراحت بود؟ - .نه -
You sure?
مطمئني؟
She doesn't look too happy.
.بنظر زياد خوشحال نمياد
Didn't you have to get up early?
نميخواستي صبح زود بيدار شي؟
I'm doing too much foryou tonight.
.امشب خيلي دارم بهت لطف ميكنم
- Maybe it means something. - Yeah. That you've got a nerve.
.شايد اين يه معني داره - .آره. كه تو عصبي هستي -
It's just for a minute.
.فقط براي يه دقيقه ست
Long enough for my friend Nuria to admit defeat.
اونقدر ميمونم كه دوستم نوريا .شكست رو قبول كنه
This is my place.
.اينجا خونه ي منه
- Don't dare laugh at it. - Why would I laugh?
.بهش نخندي - را بايد بخندم؟ -
It's nothing special, but it's cheap.
يز خاصي نداره .ولي خيلي ارزونه
- Do you like clowns? - They're not clowns.
دلقكا رو دوست داري؟ - .اونا دلقك نيستند -
They're mime artists.
.هنرمنداي شكلك بازي هستن
Pancho!
!انو
- I've got a cat. - I hate cats.
.يه ربه دارم - .از ربه ها متنفرم -
They're almost as false as actresses.
.اونا هم مثه هنريشه ها دروغي هستن
Says the caterer.
.يه يشخدمت اينو ميه
How do you pay for this?
ول اينجا رو طوري ميدي؟
Do your parents help? Do you work?
در و مادرت كمكت ميكنن؟ كار ميكني؟
He's real nosy, isn't he, Pancho?
.اون خيلي حرف ميزنه نه، انو؟
I'm an arms dealer.
.اسلحه قااق ميكنم
Fancy that! I always wanted to know how arms dealers lived.
قدر جالب! هميشه دوست داشتم بدونم .قااقياي اسلحه طوري زندي ميكنن
Now you do.
.حالا ديه ميدوني
How can I explain it to you?
طوري ميتونم برات توضيح بدم؟
You wouldn't understand. Even I don't understand.
تو نمي فهمي .حتي خودمم نمي فهمم
She was making coffee and I started snooping around.
اون داشت قهوه درست ميكرد .و من اطراف رو ديد ميزدم
Suddenly, I got this stupid feeling a lot ofpeople get.
يهو، احساس احمقانه اي كه خيلي از .مردم دارش ميشن بهم دست داد
Wel l, I I i ke it.
.خب، من كه خوشم مياد
- What didyou feel? - That I loved her.
ي رو احساسي كردي؟ - .اينكه دوسش دارم -
- God, I'm even embarrassed to say it. - I d id n't hear you.
.خداجون، حتي از فتنش خجالت ميكشم - .صداتو نشنيدم -
I said I like your place.
.فتم خونتو دوست دارم
And I like yours. Let's swap.
منم خونه ي تو رو دوست دارم .بيا معامله كنيم
You wouldn't like it tomorrow morning.
.فردا صبح ازش خوشت نمياد
I said it because of the decor.
.من فتم به خاطر دكورش خوشم مياد
Your place is more personal.
.خونت بيشتر شخصيه
- And warmer. - Warmer?
.و رمتر - رمتر؟ -
- Yes. - You think my house is cold?
.آره - فكر ميكني خونه ي من سرد و بي روحه؟ -
- A bit. - And am I?
.يه خرده - من ي؟ -
- I don't know. - You said my house seemed cold.
.نمي دونم - .تو فتي خونه ي من سرد و بيروحه -
Ifyou're waiting for me to list your virtues, hard luck.
اه منتظر مني تا خوبيهات رو .بشمارم، در اشتباهي
You thinkyou're real smart.
.فكر ميكني خيلي باهوشي
- Maybe. - Well, you're wrong.
.شايد - .خب، اشتباه ميكني -
I don't need you to list my virtues.
.نيازي ندارم تو خوبيامو بشماري
No, I'm sure you know what they are.
.نه، مطمئنم ميدوني اونا ي هستند
- But you'd like me to see them, too. - So you say.
.ولي دوست داري منم اونا رو ببينم - .اينو تو ميي -
I'm not going to argue about it.
.نميخوام دربارش باهات كل كل كنم
- Just as well. You'd lose. - Oh, yeah?
.ه بهتر. ون مي بازي - اوه، آره؟ -
But I don't want to argue either. I propose we do the opposite.
.ولي منم نمي خوام کل کل کنم .نظرت يه برعکسش رو انجام بديم
- We don't argue? - We show our defects.
کل کل نکنيم؟ - .عيب هامون رو نشون بديم -
Great!
!محشره
I hope you're being fair.
.اميدوارم منصف باشي
This is absolutely you.
.دقيقاً شده شبيه خودت
Well, mine is finished.
.خب، مال من تموم شد
Fuck! That's how you see me?
!لعنت منو اين طوري مي بيني؟
- Did I go too far? - Sign it.
زياده روي کردم؟ - .امضاش کن -
Let's see mine.
.بذار نقاشي خودمو ببينم
It's lovely!
!دوست داشتنيه
- It's not a caricature. - You see.
.اين که کاريکاتور نيست - .معلومه -
You draw beautifully.
.خيلي خوب کشيدي
- I'll sell it to you. - Miser. How much?
.بهت مي فروشمش - اي خسيس. قدر؟ -
As it's you, I'll sell it for...
، حالا ون تو هستي ...در ازاي
a kiss.
.يه بوس
That smile's going to kill me!
!اين خنده ت منو مي کُشه
It would be wrong ifwe did anything tonight.
امشب درست نيست .که کاري بکنيم
- Why? - Pelayo. Remember?
را؟ - لايو. يادته؟ -
Your best friend.
.بهترين دوستت
He doesn't have to find out. Besides, he'd do the same.
.لازم نيست که اون بفهمه .تازه، اونم بود همين کارو مي کرد
I see friendship really matters to you.
مي بينم که دوستي .واقعا برات مهمه
It does. That's why I wouldn't tell him.
.معلومه .براي همين بهش نميم
Some people...
...بعضي آدما
say that they would be happy with a normal life span.
مين که با طول عمري طبيعي .شاد خواهند بود
But "normal" means different things, depending on--
، اما "طبيعي" مفاهيم متفاوتي داره ...بسته به
What are you looking at?
به ي ناه مي کني؟
I'm watching TV.
.دارم تلويزيون مي بينم
The Romans, for instance, lived only 25 years.
، براي مثال، رومي ها .تنها 25 سال عمر مي کردند
Today...
...امروزه
that figure has tripled, which means that--
، اين رقم سه برابر شده ...که اين بدين معنيه که
- What the fuck is he on about? - I saw this before.
درباره ي داره زر مُفت ميزنه؟ - .اين برنامه رو قبلا ديدم -
It's about cryonization.
.درباره منجمد سازي بدنه
Cryo what?
منجمد ي؟
When they freeze you or something.
يعني بدن آدم رو .مثلاً منجمد مي کنن
Like Walt Disney.
.مثل والت ديسني
Wow, that's cold!
!واي، قدر سرده
Hey, you!
!هي، تو
There won't be a landslide.
.اين صخره فرو نمي ريزه
It isn't dangerous. The ground is firm here and very solid.
خطرناک نيست. اينجا .زمين محکم و سفته
- Are you leaving? - I'm going home. Here's my number.
داري ميري؟ - .ميرم خونه. اين شماره منه -
But I'll call tomorrow.
.ولي فردا بهت زن ميزنم
What for?
براي ي؟
All right, I won't call.
.باشه، زن نمي زنم
- Cesar? - What is it?
سزار؟ - يه؟ -
Come here. I want to tell you a secret.
.بيا اينجا .مي خوام يه رازي رو بهت بم
Hello, darling.
.سلام، عزيزم
Did you follow me?
منو تعقيب کردي؟
Of course I didn't.
.معلومه که نه
But I had the feeling we'd meet.
.ولي حس کردم که همديه رو مي بينيم
- How was the brunette? - Good. Why?
مو مشکيه طور بود؟ - خوب بود. طور مه؟ -
From your face, I'd say you didn't sleep with her.
از قيافه ت معلومه .که باهاش نخوابيدي
Let me guess. You didn't sleep with her, but you don't mind.
بذار حدس بزنم. باهاش نخوابيدي .ولي برات مهم نيست
You have all the time in the world for that.
براي اين کار .يه عالمه وقت داري
And I bet you're seeing her tomorrow.
.و شرط مي بندم فردا مي خواي ببينيش
- Brilliant. - Aren't I? There's more.
.ه عالي - .مه نيستم؟ هنوزم هست -
- Well? - I scored at the party, too.
خب؟ - .منم تو جشن يه نفرو يدا کردم -
But he wasn't up for it, so I'm still hot for it.
، ولي آماده اون کار نبود .براي همين هنوز آتيشم روشنه
- And? - And until you meet up again...
و؟ - ...و تا وقتي دوباره شاهزاده خانمت -
with your Miss Universe, you could have fun.
، رو ملاقات کني .مي توني خوش بذروني
No. I think I prefer to go home and sleep.
نه. به نظرم بهتر باشه .برم خونه بخوابم
Come on, Cesar. It's your birthday.
.دست بردار، سزار .امروز تولدته
- Skip it. I'm going home. - What's up, Cesar?
.بي خيالش. ميرم خونه - ي شده، سزار؟ -
Are you scared?
مي ترسي؟
- Want some of this? - No, thanks.
از اينا مي خواي؟ - .نه، ممنون -
Sure, act innocent now.
.باشه، حالا سوسول بازي دربيار
I don't need that to enjoy myself.
من براي خوش ذروندن .به اون نيازي ندارم
I see that.
.که اين طور
That's not a good idea.
.فکر خوبي نيست
Do what you want.
.هر کاري مي خواي بکن
What's happiness for you?
شادي براي تو يه؟
- What? - For me, this is happiness.
ي؟ - .براي من، شادي اينه -
Being here with you. What about you?
.اينجا با تو بودن تو ي؟
I can't handle heavy conversations right now.
.الان از س صحبت هاي قلمبه سلمبه برنميام
Your thoughts are somewhere else, right?
فکرت جاي ديه ايه، نه؟
Maybe.
.شايد
One thing really bothers me.
.يه يزي واقعاً منو اذيت ميکنه
- What? - You know nothing about me.
ي؟ - .تو هيي از من نمي دوني -
Except my name's Nuria and I'm a good fuck.
غير از اين که اسمم نورياست .و (همبستر) خيلي خوب حال ميدم
Two important things.
.دو يز مهم
You don't know my address or telephone number.
آدرس خونه من .يا شماره تلفنم رو بلد نيستي
We have to start somewhere. I'm going to see your house now.
.بايد از يه جاي شروع کنيم ديه .الان مي خوام خونه ت رو ببينم
It's not far.
.ديه داريم مي رسيم
Tell me something.
.بو ببينم
Do you believe in God?
به خدا اعتقاد داري؟
- Hello.
.سلام -
- How are you? - You got home all right?
حالت طوره؟ - به سلامت رسيدي خونه؟ -
Yeah. Well, I had a horrible dream.
.آره. خب، خواب ترسناکي ديدم
That you never saw me again.
.که ديه هي وقت منو نمي بيني
Yes. I came out ofyour house, go to my car...
، آره تو رويامم از خونه ت که بيرون اومدم ...رفتم طرف ماشينم
and that crazy bitch has been following me.
.و ديدم اون زنيکه منو تعقيب مي کرده
- Who, that Nuria? - Yes.
کي، نوريا؟ - .آره -
She comes over and says, "Want a lift? "
، اومد يشم و فت "سواري مي خواي؟"
She goes on so much I don't know how to say no.
خيلي اصرار مي کنه .منم نمي دونم طو بم نه
So I get in the car, she drives faster and faster...
، س سوار ماشينش ميشم ...اون به مرور سريع تر رانندي مي کنه
and kills herself.
.و خودشو مي کُشه
- With me inside. - That's horrible.
.منم کنارش بودم - .وحشتناکه -
But the worst part...
...ولي بدترين قسمت
is that my face is completely destroyed...
...اينه که هره من کاملا نابود ميشه
Iike "The Phantom of the Opera."
".مثل رمان "شبح ارا
I couldn't wake up.
.نمي تونستم بيدار بشم
I was a monster.
.يه هيولا شده بودم
You're a monster anyway.
.بازم يه هيولايي
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah. I'm a monster, too.
اوه، آره؟ - .آره. منم يه هيولام -
Look.
.ببين
How was your house?
خونه ت طور بود؟
Was anyone left?
کسي مونده بود؟
Left where?
کجا مونده بود؟
In your house. There was a party, remember?
.توي خونه ت جشن تولدت بود، يادته؟
A party?
جشن تولد؟
Dreaming is shit.
.خواب ديدن خيلي رنده
Unless the dream was nice.
.مه اين که خواب خوشي بوده باشه
In the park, children playing, a girl who lovesyou.
، توي ارک، به ها بازي مي کنن .يه دختري که دوستت داره
That's why.
.اين ميشه يه يزي
Then you wake up andyou want to die.
بعدش که آدم بيدار ميشه .دلش مي خواد بميره
At first, I didn 't even have the strength to react.
اولش، حتي قدرت نداشتم .که واکنشي نشون بدم
I'd been in a coma for three weeks.
.سه هفته توي کما بودم
You were lucky.
.خيلي شانس آوردي
You could've died like Nuria.
.ممکن بود با نوريا کشته بشي
And what? I would've been better off.
ه فايده؟ .همون بهتر که مي مُردم
Didyou see her body?
تو جسدش رو ديدي؟
- I never d id. - You think she didn't die?
.من که اصلاً نديدم - فکر مي کني اون نمرده؟ -
I'm like you.
.منم مثل تو هستم
I only believe what I see.
.فقط يه يزي که مي بينم اعتقاد دارم
Cesar, show me your face, please.
، سزار، خواهش ميکنم .صورتت رو به من نشون بده
- What for? - Look.
براي ي؟ - .ببين -
It's true you had an accident. It's true...
.درسته که تصادف کردي ...درسته که
that you were disfigured, but not anymore.
، صورتت از بين رفته بود .ولي ديه نه
Take that off. The doctors fixed you.
.اون نقابو بردار .دکترها صورتت رو درست کردن
They didn't have a fucking clue!
!اونا هي ُه کاري يي نتونستن بُکنن
In the accident, you didn't lose just skin and some muscle.
تو تصادف، تنها وست .و ماهيه ت رو از دست ندادي
The blow was so severe it caused a multiple fracture of the skull.
ضربه اون قدر شديد بوده که .باعث ندين شکستي در جمجمه شده
We secured the osseous structure with metal wires...
ما ساختار استخواني رو ...با سيم هاي فلزي محکم کرديم
and over that, we reinserted the muscles...
، و روي اون ...ماهيه هايي رو که مي تونستيم
we could still retrieve.
.بازيابي کنيم، دوباره جاذاري کرديم
Yes, very nice, but I know all that.
، بله، خيلي خوبه .ولي همه اينا رو مي دونم
I've had it explained to me 1 50 times.
.اينو 150 بار براي من توضيح دادين
But you never say when you'll operate.
ولي هي وقت نميين .که مي خواين عملم کنين
- I've been waiting two months. - But we've operated three times.
.من دو ماهه منتظرم - .ولي ما سه بار عمل کرديم -
I wouldn't call that an operation. I'd call it--
.اسم اونا رو که نميشد ذاشت عمل ...اسمش ميشه
Well, I don't know what you'd call it.
.من نمي دونم ي بهشون ميين
The symmetry isn't perfect...
...تقارن صورتت کامل نيست
but what we've done with your face is, if I may say so...
، ولي کاري که تا حالا براي صورتتون انجام داديم ...مي تونم بم
a craftsman's job.
.شاهکار بوده
We can't work on skin which is pure scars.
ما نمي تونيم روي صورتي کار کنيم .که ر از زخم و شکافه
No, no, there must be some way.
.نه، نه، بايد يه راهي باشه
- What? - "What? "
ه راهي؟ - "ه راهي؟" -
You're the doctors, aren't you?
شما دکترين، مه نه؟
A transplant, whatever!
!يوندي، يزي
There's a problem with fibrosis, ifwe operate again...
، بافت ها بيش از حد رشد کردن ...اه دوباره عمل کنيم
we may just cause further damage.
.ممکنه صرفاً آسيب رو بيشتر کنيم
We'd need millimetric precision...
...به دقت ميليمتري نياز منديم
and as of today it's impossible.
.و تا به امروز، اين غيرممکنه
Let's look at this. I'm not an idiot.
.ببينيد .من احمق نيستم
Today, people change their breasts.
.اين روزها، مردم اندازه سينه هاشون رو تغيير ميدن
They have hair implants.
.روي سرشون مو مي کارن
They even change the color of their skin.
.حتي رن وستشون رو تغيير ميدن
Are you saying that on the threshold of the year 2000...
يعني ميين ...در آستانه سال 2000
you can't do a simple operation and sort out this fuck-up?
نمي تونين با يه عمل ساده اين تِرکمون کاري رو درست کنين؟
- It isn't so simple, Cesar. Remember-- - Don't patronize me!
...اين قدرها هم آسون نيست، سزار. يادت باشه - !با من مثل به ها رفتار نکن -
Stop treating me like a child!
!به نيستم که اين حرف ها رو بهم مي زنين
I'm not just any patient.
.من با بقيه مريض ها فرق دارم
And this isn't a welfare hospital.
.اين بيمارستان هم خيريه نيست
I'm willing to pay any amount.
.هر قدر بخواين ول ميدم
You're in charge.
.تو مسئول بيمارستاني
They say you're the best in your field.
.مين تو اين زمينه بهتريني
Well, invent something. Experiment with me.
.خب، يه يزي اختراع کن .رو من آزمايشش کن
I've seen patients who've lost all their features...
مريض هايي ديدم که ...همه اعضاي صورتشون رو از دست دادن
who can't even talk.
.حتي نمي تونستن حرف بزنن
At least you can lookyourself in the eyes.
.حداقل مي توني به خودت ناه کني
What good is that?
ه فايده اي داره؟
Every time I look in the mirror, I want to die.
، هر بار که تو آينه ناه مي کنم .دلم مي خواد بميرم
Your case isn't so serious.
.مورد تو خيلي جدي نيست
Just learn to accept it.
.فقط ياد بير اونو بذيري
And who will accept me?
و کي منو مي ذيره؟
Will you explain to the people who look at me in the street?
تو به آدم هايي که تو خيابون به من ناه مي کنن توضيح ميدي؟
Will you tell them that looks aren't important?
بهشون ميي که قيافه مهم نيست؟
That beauty is on the inside?
زيبايي تو وجود آدمه؟
We'd like to show you something.
.مي خوايم يه يزي نشونت بديم
What is this?
اين يه؟
A facial prosthesis.
.يه هره مصنوعي
We use it in extreme cases of rejection like yours.
در موردهاي عدم ذيرشي .مثل تو ازش استفاده مي کنيم
This is shit!
!اين مسخره س
It's not the best solution...
...اين بهترين راه حل نيست
but it's all we can do for the moment.
ولي اين تنها کاريه .که فعلا از عهده مون برمياد
I want a face! Not a mask!
!من صورت مي خوام !نه يه نقاب
I don't work miracles.
.من نمي تونم معجزه کنم
That's what the bastard said.
.اون حرمزاده اين حرفو بهم زد
But in the end, they did.
.ولي در آخر، تونستن
Did what?
يکار کنن؟
Work a miracle.
.معجزه کردن
So it seems.
.اين طور به نظر مياد
So it seems? Things are or they aren't?
اين طور به نظر مياد؟ .بالاخره يا هست يا نيست
- Did they do it or not? - I'm tired. Why don't you go?
تونستن يا نتونستن؟ - خسته ام. را نميري؟ -
I'll be back on Tuesday. Want anything?
.سه شنبه برمي ردم يزي لازم نداري؟
- No. - All right. See you on Tuesday.
.نه - .باشه. سه شنبه مي بينمت -
A pad and a pencil.
.يه مداد و دفتر
But don't tell them. I don't want to owe them anything.
.ولي بهشون نو .نمي خوام مديونشون بشم
Have I changed so much?
اين قدر تغيير کردم؟
Because I recognize you.
.ون من تو رو مي شناسم
How are you?
حالت طوره؟
"How are you? "
"حالت طوره؟"
You're playing a part now, but I don't know what. Your lips are smiling.
الان داري نقش بازي مي کني، ولي نمي دونم .ه نقشي. لب هات داره لبخند ميزنه
- But your eyes are trembling. - What?
.ولي ترس تو شمات موج ميزنه - ي؟ -
You're really very good as an actress.
.تو بازيري واقعا خيلي خوب هستي
I asked you how you were. You didn't answer.
.ازت رسيدم حالت طوره .خودت جواب ندادي
I'm alive. How should I be?
.زنده ام طور بايد باشم؟
And I'm tired.
.و خسته ام
Tired ofwaiting foryou to call, even to say "Tough luck."
، خسته از بس منتظر تماست موندم ".حتي براي فتن "بدبخت بياره
- I was busy. - Bullshit!
.سرم شلوغ بود - !شِرُ و وِر نو -
I was afraid you'd feel uncomfortable if I rang.
مي ترسيدم اه زن بزنم .احساس راحتي نکني
You were afraid you'd feel uncomfortable.
مي ترسيدي که .خودت احساس راحتي نکني
Afraid you couldn't look me in the face, like now.
مي ترسيدي، مثل الان .نتوني تو صورتم ناه کني
That's not true.
.اين حقيقت نداره
I've often dreamed of this moment.
.اغلب خواب اين لحظه رو مي ديدم (روياي ذهنم)
What moment?
ه لحظه اي؟
The moment we'd meet again.
.لحظه اي که دوباره همديه رو ببينيم
In my dream, we were just like this.
، توي خوابم .درست مثل الان بوديم
Here, in the park.
.اينجا، توي ارک
Although something was different.
.ولي يه يزي فرق داشت
What?
ي؟
It wasn't raining.
.بارون نمي اومد
I have to go, Cesar.
.من بايد برم، سزار
- What are you doing tomorrow night? - Studying. I'm very busy.
فردا شب ي کار مي کني؟ - .مطالعه مي کنم. سرم خيلي شلوغه -
- It's Friday. We could meet. - I've got a lot to do.
.فردا جمعه است. مي تونيم همديه رو ببينيم - .خيلي کار دارم -
All right, so long.
.باشه، به سلامت
Cesar!
!سزار
We'll meet ifyou want.
.اه بخواي همديه رو مي بينيم
Ifyou want.
.اه تو بخواي
As soon as there is the slightest possibility ofdeath...
به محض اين که کمترين ...احتمال مر وجود داشته باشد
the stabilization and transport team goes into action.
روه تثبيت و انتقال .وارد عمل مي شود
Once the client is declared legally dead...
وقتي مشتري ...طبق قانون مُرده شناخته شد
he is put into a maintenance capsule...
...او درون کسول محافظ ذاشته مي شود
and the transport legalities are sorted out.
و مراحل قانوني .انتقال او انجام مي شود
In the storeroom in Arizona in the U.S.A...
در مخزن واقع در ...آريزونا در ايالات متحده آمريکا
a team ofspecialists prepare the body for final freezing.
روهي از متخصصان جسد را .براي انجماد نهايي آماده مي کنند
Among other measures...
...در ميان دير يشيري ها
blood is replaced by a solution which preserves the organs.
يک محلول جايزين خون مي شود .تا اندام ها حفظ شوند
Finally...
...در آخر
the client is put in the capsule....
...مشتري درون کسول ذاشته مي شود
where he will remain until medicine can reenergize him.
و در انجا باقي مي ماند .تا زماني که علم زشکي او را زنده کند
To be honest, I'd have to think it over.
، راستش رو بخوايد .بايد در اين خصوص فکر کنم
It's hard to accept the idea.
.قبول کردن اين کار خيلي سخته
How should we view it?
طور بايد بهش ناه کنيم؟
We are, undoubtedly, facing a major development...
، ما بدون شک ...با يشرفت عظيمي روبرو هستيم
a new challenge for humanity.
.که الش جديدي براي بشريت هست
It's understandable that the first reaction is rejection.
قابل درکه که اولين .واکنش مردم رد اين مسئله باشه
We have now got the means to do it.
.الان وسايل انجام اين کار رو داريم
We've got the technology.
.تکنولوژي اون رو داريم
But, above all, we have sufficient moral maturity...
اما مهمتر از همه، داراي ...بلوغ معنوي کافي هستيم
to understand what this new step means...
که بدونيم اين قدم جديد ...براي تکامل انسان
for human evolution, to look at the future...
، ه معنايي داره ...براي نريستن به آينده
and put an end to certain meaningless taboos...
و ايان دادن به ...تابوهاي بي معني خاصي
inherited from ancient religions...
...که از مذاهب باستاني به ارث رسيدن
old and useless memories.
.خاطرات قديمي و بلا استفاده
Thankyou for speaking to us.
.ممنون که در اين برنامه حضور يدا کردين
And thankyou to our audience--
...و از بينندان عزيز متشکريم که
- Hi.
.سلام -
- What's that? - Shit, isn't it?
اين يه؟ - مسخره س، نه؟ -
But they suggested I wear it in case of infection.
ولي بهم فتن براي .جلويري از عفونت اينو بوشم
Well, kid, what're you up to?
خب، سر، ي کار مي کني؟
Arguing with doctors all day.
.تمام روز با دکترها جر و بحث مي کنم
- You should go out more. - I'm trying.
.بايد بيشتر بري بيرون - .دارم سعي مي کنم -
- What're you having? - Rum and Coke. You want one?
ي مي خورين؟ - عرق نيشکر و کوکا. مي خوري؟ -
- Yes. - I'll get you one.
.آره - .يکي برات مي يرم -
I'm going to the bathroom.
.من ميرم دستشويي
- Take that off. - Why?
.اونو از رو صورتت بردار - واسه ي؟ -
Don't you realize you won't be able to hide your face?
متوجه نيستي که نمي توني صورتت رو مخفي کني؟
I told you, it's to stop infections.
، بهت فتم که .براي عفونته
Sure.
.معلومه
Ifyou're embarrassed, just go. Nobody asked you to come.
.اه تو رو خجالت ميدم، مي توني بري .کسي ازت نخواست که بياي
- Sofia did. - What?
.سوفيا که اين کارو کرد - ي؟ -
- She didn't want to be alone with you. - Why not?
.نمي خواست با تو تنها باشه - را؟ -
- You're giving her a hard time. - I'm having a hard time.
.داري اونو عذاب ميدي - .من دارم عذاب مي کشم -
Talk to a psychologist, or to me.
.با يه روانشناس حرف بزن، يا با من
Don't take it out on a girl you met once.
جلوي يه دختري که قبلاً .تو رو ديده اونو برندار
Did she say that?
اون اين حرفو بهت زد؟
- Bitch! - Come back!
!جنده - !بررد -
Whiskey and Coke.
.ويسکي و کوکا
- What whiskey? - What did you say?
ه ويسکي؟ - ي فتي؟ -
What whiskey?
ه نوع ويسکي؟
Why don't you ask me to my face, son of a bitch?
را وقتي باهام حرف ميزني به صورتم ناه نمي کني، حرومزاده؟
Ballantine's.
.بالنتاينز
- Same again. - No, this one's on me.
.يکي ديه بده - .نه، اين يکي رو مهمون من باش -
- Why? -Just is.
را؟ - .همين طوري -
Fix your face, man!
!صورتت رو درست کن، سر
- Hello.
.سلام -
- Where were you? - Around.
کجا بودي؟ - .همين دور و بر -
Pelayo went to look foryou.
.لايو رفت دنبالت برده
And I came to look foryou.
.و من اومدم دنبال تو بردم
Why?
را؟
To-- No reason.
.تا... همين جوري
To buy you a drink.
.تا... برات يه نوشيدني بيرم
- Want a drink? - No, thanks.
نوشيدني ميل داري؟ - .نه، ممنون -
Can you tell I'm elbowing in?
ميتوني بي دارم درشو باز ميكنم؟
The thing is, I've got a problem.
.آخه يه مشکل دارم
A girl's chasing me, and I need some help to get rid ofher.
يه دختر دنبالمه... و براي خلاص شدن .از شرش کمک مي خوام
Shit, shit, shit! She's coming this way.
!لعنتي! لعنتي! لعنتي .داره مياد اين طرف
Don't look. Don't look.
.ناه نکن. ناه نکن
You carry on talking, act as if he weren't here.
تو به صحبت کردن ادامه بده .جوري رفتار کن که انار اون اينجا نيست
I mean, as if I were here.
.منظورم اين بود که من اينجا نيستم
Keep talking. Tra-la-lee, tra-la-la.
.صحبت کن
What a lovely conversation we're having.
.ه صحبت عاشقانه اي است
So that's it, here we are...
...خب حالا شد، ما اينجاييم
having a bit of a chat about life.
.يه صحبت کوولو در مورد زندي
That's enough!
!ديه کافيه
Where the hell were you?
کدوم وري بودي؟
Around.
.دور و ور
I'm leaving. I'm tired.
.من دارم ميرم. خسته ام
You two stay ifyou want.
.شما دو تا اه دلتون ميخواد ميتونين بمونين
Well, this is where I leave you.
.خب، اينجا جاييه که من ازتون جدا ميشم
- I'll see you home. - No, I live very close.
.ميرسونمت خونه - .نه، من همين نزديکيا زندي ميکنم -
- I've got the motorbike. - No.
.من موتور دارم - .نه -
- Don't be silly. - Lay off, Pelayo.
.احمق نشو - .بيخيال، لايو -
She wants to go on her own.
.اون ميخواد تنهايي بره
Shut up. You're drunk.
.خفه شو. تو مستي
I might be drunk, but I'm not an idiot.
.ممکنه مست باشم ولي احمق نيستم
- Anyway, I'm not drunk. - Really, you needn't bother.
.به هر حال، من مست نيستم - .واقعا، نميخواد اذيت بشي -
- As you wish. - You're the one who's drunk.
.هر جور ميلته - .اوني که مسته تويي -
We'll call you to meet some other day.
باهات تماس مييريم .تا همديه رو ملاقات کنيم
All right. We could go to the movies.
.باشه. بريم فيلم ببينيم
- You hear? - Great!
شنيدي؟ - !عاليه -
Well, that's it, then.
...خب ، همين ديه، س
No, don't kiss me. You might get poisoned by my drunken breath.
نه، منو بوس نکن. ممکنه با نفس يه آدم .مست مسموم بشي
Well, we'll meet up soon.
.خب، به زودي همديه رو ميبينيم
Sure.
.البته
We'll meet up soon.
.به زودي همديه رو ميبينيم
It's not cold.
.سرد که نيست
Well...
...خب
I'm gonna have to go.
.من بايد برم
Where are you going?
کجا ميري؟
I've just remembered my bike is back there.
.تازه يادم اومده که موتورم اون شته
- I'll go with you. - No. Why? You're almost home now.
.منم باهات ميام - .نه. را؟ تو تقريبا رسيدي خونه -
- See you tomorrow. - Pelayo, wait a minute.
.فردا ميبينمت - .لايو، يه لحظه صبر کن -
What?
يه؟
I don't know.
.نميدونم
You drank too much. We'll talk tomorrow ifyou want.
، تو خيلي مستي .اه دلت خواست فردا ميتونيم باهم حرف بزنيم
- Tomorrow I'll wish I were dead. - You won't.
.فردا آرزو ميکنم که مرده باشم - .نه -
You just need to rest.
.فقط نياز به استراحت داري
Pelayo!
!لايو
You're my best friend.
.تو بهترين دوست مني
Son of a bitch!
.حرومزاده
Open your eyes.
.شماتو باز کن
Cesar.
.سِزار
It's me.
.منم
Sofia!
!سوفيا
- What are you doing here? - Forgive me.
اين جا يکار ميکني؟ - .منو ببخش -
Why?
را؟
I love you.
.من دوستت دارم
Come on.
.بيا
- What's wrong? - Nothing.
ي شده؟ - .هيي -
I still can't believe this is really happening.
من هنوزم باورم نيمشه که اين .واقعا داره اتفاق ميفته
Where's Pelayo?
لايو کجاست؟
I don't know. He went with you, didn't he?
.نميدونم اون با تو اومد، مه نه؟
Yes.
.آره
Of course.
.البته
Come on.
.بيا
God, what a sensation!
!خداجون، ه احساسيه
Ofwhat?
از ي؟
Do you ever feel you've lived something before?
تا بحال احساس کردي که قبلا زندي کردي؟
Yes.
.آره
Why is that?
دليلش يه؟
They say it's a lapse in the brain.
.مين که يه ذشته در مغز هست
I've been here before.
.من قبلا اينجا بودم
It usually goes away after a few seconds.
.معمولا بعد از ند ثانيه از بين ميره
I don't want it to go away.
.نميخوام که از بين بره
You've made use ofyour time.
.شما از زمانتان استفاده كردهايد
That's all there is here.
.همش همينه
Very pretty. Is it Sofia?
خيلي زيباست. اين سوفياست؟
How much longer will I be here?
قدر ديه بايد اينجا بمونم؟
No one ever knows that.
.هيشکي نميدونه
Even my worst nightmare was never like this place.
حتي بدترين کابوساي منم .شبيه اينجا نبوده
It's a psychiatric penitentiary. No more, no less.
اينجا بازداشتاه بيماران روانيه .نه کمتر نه بيشتر
- I shouldn't be here. - You're accused of murder.
.من نبايد اينجا باشم - .تو متهم به قتلي -
- I don't even know what I did. - Tell me something.
.من حتي نميدونم يکار کردم - .يه يزي بهم بو -
-Does the name Eli mean anything to you? -Eli?
اسم الي واست معنايي داره؟ - الي؟
You know a girl with that name?
دختري با اين اسم ميشناسي؟
No. Why do you ask?
نه. واسه ي ميرسي؟
It seems you kept repeating it last night.
.ون ديشب همش اينو تکرار ميکردي
I guess I was dreaming.
.فکر کنم خواب ميديدم
- What did you dream? - I can't remember.
ي خواب ميديدي؟ - .يادم نمياد -
- It could be important. - How could it be important?
.ممکنه مهم باشه - طوري ميتونه مهم باشه؟ -
Look, I can prove you didn't know what you were doing...
ببين، من ميتونم ثابت کنم که تو ...نميدونستي که داري يکار ميکني
but first I have to find some explanation for all this.
ولي اول بايد يه سري توضيحات .واسه همه ي اين يزا يدا کنم
There is no explanation. I told you the other day.
هي توضيحي وجود نداره .اون روز هم بهت فتم
What did you dream, Cesar?
ي خواب ميديد سزار؟
I don't know.
.نميدونم
I only remember bits.
.فقط يه کوولوش يادم مياد
First, I'm in a kind of office.
.اول، من توي يا جايي شبيه يه دفتر هستم
A secretary shows me into another office.
.منشي منو به يه دفتر ديه راهنمايي ميکنه
There's a photo ofa sunset and a man.
.يه تصوير از غروب آفتاب و يه مرد هست
Then, I don't know.
.بعدش، نميدونم
- They show me lots ofpapers. - What papers?
.اونا يه عالمه کاغذ بهم نشون ميدن- ه کاغذايي؟ -
I don't know.
.نميدونم
But I sign them.
.ولي من امضاشون ميکنم
Does the office belong to your company?
اون دفتر متعلق به شرکت شما بوده؟
No, I don't recognize it.
.نه، من نشناختمش
You dreamed of a place you'd never been?
توي خواب (رويا) يه جايي رو ديدي که تا بحال نرفتي؟
Yes. That happens a lot, doesn't it?
آره. اين خيلي اتفاق ميفته، مه نه؟
Are they the papers you signed with the doctors?
اونا کاغذايي بودن که تو يش دکترها امضا کردي؟
No, what happened with the doctors was surreal.
.نه، اتفاقي که واسه دکترا افتاد غير واقعي بود
- Why? - They rang me to go to the hospital.
را؟ - .اونا منو بردن به بيمارستان -
When I arrived, the whole surgical team was waiting.
.وقتي من رسيدم، کل تيم جراحي منتظر بودن
Formonths, those faces had looked at me with indifference and impotence.
براي ماهها اون صورت خيلي سرد .به من نيا ميکردن
Now they were all smiles.
.الان همشون لبخند ميزنن
The same bastard who had said my case was hopeless talked about an operation.
همون آشغالي که فته بود مسئله ي من .درست شدني نيست؛ صحبت از يک عمل ميکرد
They had a new revolutionary system in the clinic now.
.اونا يه دستاه جديد توي کلينيکشون داشتن
They said that within two weeks my face would be completely reconstructed.
.اونا فتن در عرض 2 هفته شم من احيا ميشه
You didn 't believe them?
تو باور کردي؟
Not at fi rst. I thought it was just a way to get more money out of me.
اولش نه. فکر کردم اين يه راهيه .که بخوان از من ول بيشتري بيرن
But they showed me all the gad gets for the operation.
اما همه يزاي که واسه عمل بود رو .بهم نشون دادن
It looked like science fiction.
.علمي و تخيلي بود
All I could see were cables, switches, monitors.
تمام يزي که من ميتونستم ببينم .کابل و کليد برق و مانيتورا بود
Actually, I never really knew what they were going to do.
.در واقع اصلا نميدونستم ميخوان يکار کنن
But I thought I'd nothing to lose.
ولي فکر کردم که .يزي واسه از دست دادن ندارم
Those people were used to rhinoplasties...
...اونا قبلا جراح بيني
Iiposuctions, hair transplants, but my operation was much more.
ليوساکشن، کاشت مو بودن .ولي عمل من خيلي سخت تر از اين يزا بود
In less than a week...
.تو کمتر از يک هفته
my life had turned around.
.زنديم از اين رو به اون رو شد
One night, I was lying on the ground drunk, waiting to die.
يه شب، مست روي زمين دراز کشيده بودم .و منتظر مر بودم
The next morning, my dreams were coming true...
...صبحش، روياهام داشت به حقيقت مييوست
I i ke i n the movies.
.مثل تو فيلما بودم
Sofia loved me, and the doctors found the miracle cure.
سوفيا منو دوست داشت، و دکترا .يه عمل معجزه آسا رو کشف کرده بودن
I don't know. Obviously, I was suspicious.
.نميدونم .مطمئنا مشکوک شدم
Suspicious?
مشکوک؟
Ofwhom? Ofwhat?
به کي؟ به ي؟
I don't know.
.خودمم نميدونم
In life, you never know.
.تو زندي، هيوقت نميدوني
Happiness comes when you least expect it.
شادي مياد .وقتي که اصلا انتظارشو نداري
I once knew a guy who was alone in the world.
يه کسيو ميشناختم .که تنها بود
Suddenly, he was married with two daughters.
.يِهويي، ازدواج کرد و صاحب دو تا دختر شد
Fuck, you've got a strange idea of happiness.
اييدمش؛ .تو ايده ي عجيبي راجع به خوشبختي داري
Well, that depends on the individual. What's happiness foryou?
خب، بستي به شخصيت داره که خوشبختي واسه تو يه؟
Don't ask any more stupid questions.
.ديه سوال احمقانه نرس
But at that time, you were happy. Or weren't you?
ولي اون موقع، تو شاد بودي يا نبودي؟
So what? My life now is shit.
که ي؟ .زندي من الان آشغاليه
All I can do is eat, shit, sleep and dream of my memories.
تموم کاري که ميتونم بکنم خوردن و خوابيدن .و خواب ديدن خاطراتمه
It's good that you remember.
.خوبه که يادت مياد
- Well? - Well, what?
خب؟ - خب، ي؟ -
They were to remove the plates today.
.اونا ميخواستن امروز روکش رو بردارن
- And they did. - And?
.و انجام دادن - و؟ -
Well, my ears are where they should be.
.وشام جايي هست که بايد باشه
Cesar, don't scare me.
.سزار، منو نترسون
- Take off the plates. - You can do it.
.روکش رو بردار - .تو ميتوني اينکار رو انجام بدي -
How did they do it?
طوري اينکارو کردن؟
Wait.Just to say that I love you.
.صبر کن. فقط واسه اينکه بم دوستت دارم
You're going too fast...
...خيلي تند ميري
considering we met yesterday.
.فکر کن که ديروز همديه رو ديديم
Yesterday?
ديروز؟
My birthday, don't you remember?
تولدم، يادت نمياد؟
I met an incredible girl. Her name was Sofia.
من يه دختر فوق العاده رو .ديدم که اسمش « سوفيا » بود
But today I woke up feeling great...
...اما امروز با يه حس عالي بيدار شدم
and now I'm with the girl again.
.و حالا دوباره من با دختر هستم
What is it?
ي شده؟
Ifyou want me to move, you have to put in a coin.
اه ميخواي حرکت کنم، بايد .يه سکه بندازي داخلم
Ting!
!دين دون
We never appreciate the good moments till they're over.
ما هيوقت قدردان لحظه هاي خوب نيستيم .تا وقتي که تموم ميشن
Maybe that's why they're good moments.
شايد همين دليلشه که .اونا لحظات خوب ناميده ميشن
- We don't stop to think about them. - Perhaps.
.ما از فکر کردن بهش دست بر نميدارم - .شايد -
What happened to Pelayo?
ه اتفاقي واسه لايو افتاد؟
- What's up? - Hang on a minute.
ي شد؟ - .يه لحظه صبر کن -
- That's it. - About time.
.همينه - .به موقع -
- Want anything else? - No, thanks.
يز ديه اي ميخواي؟ - .نه مُکر -
How's things, Pelayo?
اوضاع طوره لايو؟
Fine.
.خوب
Yeah.
.آره
I'm actually not as fucked up as I look.
راستش اونجوري که .به قيافم ميخوره بِاه نرفتم
I'm used to you always winning, you bastard.
همش از تو مي بردم .حرومزاده
- And Sofia isn't that great. - You said she was ideal.
.و سوفيا، عالي نيست - .تو فتي که ايده آله -
Really?
واقعا؟
I was drunk.
.مست بودم
Anyway, we're friends.
.به هر حال رفيقيم ديه
Bastard!
!حرومزاده
- What's that on your face? - What?
رو صورتت يه؟ - ي؟ -
- Fuck, there's a seam opening! - What are you on about?
!!اَاَه لعنت، يه شکافي داره باز ميشه - منظورت يه؟ -
You fucking idiot!
!مغزت باه رفته
What's the matter?
ي شده؟
I hate dreaming.
.از خواب ديدن بدم مياد
You're tickling me.
.غلغلکم ميدي
What's wrong?
ي شده؟
What is it?
يهو ي شد؟
- Where's Sofia? - What?
سوفيا کجاست؟ - ي؟ -
What have you done with Sofia?
با سوفيا يکار کردي؟
- I am Sofia. - You bitch!
.من سوفيام - !تو جنده يي -
- You're mad. You're mad. - Where is she?
.تو ديوونه اي - اون کجاست؟ -
In one minute, I'm going to call the police.
.تا يه دقيقه ديه زن ميزنم ليس
You'll be in trouble if Sofia doesn't appear.
.اه سوفيا يدا نشه تو دردسر ميفتي
So you survived the accident.
.س تو از تصادف زنده در رفتي
What accident?
ه تصادفي؟
- Whose body was it? - I didn't have an accident.
جسد کي بود؟ - .من تصادف نکردم -
No. It wasn't an accident. It was attempted murder.
نه. تصادف نبوده .اقدام به قتل بوده
A pity you didn't see my face, bitch!
!دلت به حال صورت من نسوخت، ماده س
- Why do this? How have I changed? - You haven't.
را اينکار رو ميکني؟ طوري من تغيير کردم؟ - .نکردي -
You're the same lunatic who gate-crashed my party.
همون ديوونه اي هستي که .ناخوانده وارد مهموني من شدي
I'm the girl you made love to just now. I'm Sofia.
من همونيم که تو عاشقشي .من سوفيام
Stop saying you're Sofia, do you hear?
ديه نو سوفيا هستي، فهميدي؟
Don't say her name!
!اسمشو نبر
You won't tell me where she is.
.تو بهم نميي اون کجاست
You never will.
.هيوقت نميي
Cesar.
.سِزار
I love you.
.دوستت دارم
- Hello.
.سلام -
You can go. I'll see to this.
.ميتوني بري. من بررسيش ميکنم
Right.
.خوب
Let me get this clear.
.بزار اينو بفهمم سزار
- Where were you last night? - At home. I told that gentleman.
ديشب کجا بودي؟ - .خونه، به اون آقا هم فتم -
At home. With whom?
خونه. با کي؟
- With a girl. - The girl just questioned?
.با يه دختر - از اون دختر بازجويي شد؟ -
No, that's another girl. I was with Sofia.
نه يه دختر ديه اس .من با سوفيا بودم
The girl I spoke to was Sofia.
اون دختري که .من باهاش صحبت کردم اسمش سوفيا بود
Yes, that's what she says, but it's a lie.
.آره، اون دروغ ميه
- Who is she then? - She's Nuria.
س اون کيه؟ - .اون نوريا هست -
Nuria what?
نورياي ي؟
I don't know. She never told me her surname.
.نميدونم .هيوقت نام فاميلشو بهم نفت
Let's see.
.بذار ببينم
You were at home with a girl called Sofia, and suddenly--
...تو خونه با يه دختر به اسم سوفيا بودي و يهُو
I go to the bathroom, come back, and she's in Sofia's place.
رفتم دستشويي .و برشتم اون تو جاي سوفيا بود
Where's Sofia?
سوفيا کجاست؟
Ask Nuria. She's pretending to be her.
از نوريا برس .اون تظاهر ميکنه که سوفياست
You don't know her surname?
تو نام فاميلشو نميدوني؟
But who do you believe, her or me?
شما ادعاي کيو باور ميکنين، اون يا من؟
Listen, that girl's papers are all in order. We've let her go.
وش کن، مدارک اون دختر تکميله .ما بهش اجازه ميديم بره
- You've what? - And I assure you she's called Sofia.
شما ي؟ - .و بهت اطمينان ميدم که اسمش سوفياست -
Sofia Cueto, and she lives at number 2, Quiros St.
سوفيا کوئتو، و تو خيابون کوئيروس .شماره 2 زندي ميکنه
- No! - No, what?
!نه - نه، ي؟ -
Well, yes, but that's another girl. I know the real Sofia.
خب، آره، اما اون يه دختر ديه اس .من سوفياي واقعي رو ميشناسم
Then tell me where she is.
.س بهم بو کجاست
Because, legally the girl you're talking about...
...اون دختري که شما در موردش صحبت ميکني
only exists in your imagination.
.فقط تو تصورات شماست
- I don't believe this. - And another thing.
.من باور نميکنم - .و يه يز ديه -
The girl looks as if she'd been hit.
.به نظر ميرسه که اون کتک خورده
She was in my house supplanting my girlfriend!
اون توي خونه ي من بود !به جاي دوست دخترم
I don't know why, but she wouldn't press charges.
نميدونم را .ولي اون شکايت نميکنه
Fucking great! So now she's the victim!
!اَن توي اَن عالي يي شده !حالا اون قرباني حساب ميشه
Tell me. Are you on drugs?
بهم بو؛ مواد مصرف کردي؟
- God! - You were under psychiatric care.
!!اي خدا - .شما تحت درمان رواني بودين -
My face was destroyed in a car crash she caused!
هره ي من به خاطر تصادفي که !اون باعثش بود، داغون شد
Your face looks fine.
.صورتت خوب به نظر ميرسه
Because--
...به خاطر
It doesn't matter. I've got nothing more to say.
.مهم نيست .ديه يزي واسه فتن ندارم
Young man.
.مرد جوان
I'd advise you to see a psychiatrist.
.يشنهاد ميکنم به يه روانزشک مراجعه کني
Are you an idiot?
ديوونه شدي؟
- What the fuck is this? - What do you mean?
اين ه وهيه؟ - منظورت يه؟ -
Ifyou wanted to fuck her up, there are other ways to do it!
اه ميخواستي باش بدي .راههاي ديه اي هم بود
- Keep away from Sofia! - It isn't Sofia. It's Nuria!
!سمت سوفيا نرو - !اون سوفيا نيست. نورياست -
Nuria's dead!
!نوريا مرده
Calm down, oryou'll be sleeping in a cell tonight!
!آروم باش، ورنه امشبو اينجا مهموني
Don't ever talk to me again!
.ديه باهام صحبت نکن
I don't know what the cops told you, but Nuria is alive!
.نميدونم ليسا بهت ي فتن ولي نوريا زندس
The cops didn't tell me, Sofia did.
ليسا بهم نفتن؛ .سوفيا فت
Listen, you spoke to her by phone, didn't you?
، وش کن، تلفني باهاش صحبت کردي مه نه؟
- Let go! - It wasn't Sofia.
!ول کن - .اون سوفيا نبود -
Nuria can imitate her voice. She took her ID, her apartment.
نوريا ميتونه صداشو تقليد کنه .اون کارت شناساييشو برداشته، آارتمانش
It wasn't over the phone. I've just dropped her home.
شت تلفن نبود .من رسوندمش خونه
She looked like this.
.اون اين شکلي بود
Nice photo, isn't it?
عکس قشنيه نه؟
You going to say that isn't Sofia?
ميخواي بي اين سوفيا نيست؟
But that's-- Is this a joke or what?
...اما اين اين سرکاريه يا يز ديه؟
You're crazy, man.
.تو ديوونه اي
I'm crazy? I'm crazy?
من ديوونه ام؟ من ديوونه ام؟
You're the ones who are mad! You're all mad!
!شماييد که ديوونه ايد !همتون ديوونه ايد
Let go of me!
!ولم کن
God, what's happening?
خداي من، ه اتفاقي داره ميفته؟
It's my partners, right?
شرکاي منن، نه؟
They've paid you. This is a plot!
اونا بهت ول دادن !اين يه نقشه اس
Look at yourself. You haven't been right since the accident.
به خودت نياه کن؛ .تا بحال بعد تصادف خوب نبودي
Fuckyou!
!برو بابا اييدمت
Are you saying--
...داري ميي
Are you saying this is the girl you ran after the other night?
داري ميي اين همون دختريه که ...اون شب رفتي دنبالش
- Is this your ideal girl? - Yes!
اين دختر ايده آله توئه؟ - !آررره -
And you took her.
.و تو اون مال خود کردي
You need a psychiatrist!
!تو به يه روانزشک نياز داري
Problems?
مشکل داري؟
I'm in no mood, so just--
...اصلا حوصله ندارم، س فقط
There's an explanation for all this.
.يه توضيحي واسه همه ي اين يزا هست
Cesar.
.سزار
Who are you?
تو کي هستي؟
- You've seen me on TV. - What do you want?
.تو منو تو تلويزيون ديدي - ي ميخواي؟ -
I'm here to help you.
.اومدم کمکت کنم
First of all, it's very important that you calm down.
.اول از همه، خيلي مهمه که آروم باشي
Calm down?
آروم؟
You must overcome your fears and regain control.
بايد به ترسهات غلبه کني .و کنترلو بدست بيري
What control do you mean? I'm fine.
منظورت از کنترل يه؟ .من خوبم
Who says you aren't?
کي فت نيستي؟
They do. All of them.
.اونا. همشون
They think I'm mad.
.فکر ميکنن من ديوونه ام
No, of course you're not mad.
.نه، البته که نيستي
But what if I told you you were dreaming?
اما ي ميشه اه بهت بم که خواب ميديدي؟
No, no, no.
.نه، نه، نه
Why not?
را نه؟
- I know what's real, and this is real. - How do you know?
.ميدونم ي واقعيه، و اين واقعيه - طوري ميدوني؟ -
You discoveryour dreams when you wake.
.تو خوابت رو وقتي بيدار شي کشف ميکني
I just know.
.من فقط ميدونم
- My dreams are much simpler than this. - No dream is simple.
.که خواب هاي من اينقدرها هم ييده نيستن - .هي خوابي (رويايي) ساده نيست -
Look at those people.
.به اونا ناه کن
They seem to be talking about their own business.
به نظر دارن در مورد کسب و کار .خودشون حرف ميزنن
Completely unaware ofyou.
.بدون اينکه به تو توجهي کنن
And yet, they could be there because you wanted it.
با اين وجود ميتونن اونجا حضور داشته باشن .ون تو اينطور خواستي
What's more, you could have them at your complete service...
علاوه بر اين، تو ميتوني کنترل همه اونها .رو بدست بيري
or have them destroy you.
.و يا کاري کني که به تو آسيب برسونن
I want them to be quiet.
.من ميخوام اونا ساکت باشن
And you, too.
.تو هم همينطور
See?
ديدي؟
What's going on here?
ه اتفاقي افتاده؟
Someone tell me the fucking truth!
!يکي به من زِر راستشو به
The truth? Maybe you couldn't take it.
واقيعت؟ .شايد نخواي بذيريش
It had to be a setup, a big joke to drive me crazy.
حتما از قبل با هم هماهن کرده بودن .يه مسخره بازي تا منو ديوونه کنن
They all knew. Nuria, Pelayo, the police, the guy at the bar.
همه اونها خبر داشتن. نوريا، ِلايو .(ليس و اون يارو شت بار (مشروب سرا
- Who was he? - I don't know.
اون کي بود؟ - .نميدونم -
You said you saw him on TV. On what program?
.تو فتي که اونو توي تلويزيون ديدي ه برنامه اي بود؟
I don't know!
!نميدونم
I don't know. One that talked about freezing the dead.
نميدونم. برنامه اي که در مورد .انجماد مُرده صحبت مي کرد
- Freezing the dead? - Cryonization.
انجماد مُرده؟ - .کرايونيزيشن -
Like they did to Walt Disney.
.مثل کاري که با والت ديزني کردن
Maybe I can help you remember.
.شايد بتونم کمکت کنم که به ياد بياري
Is that a threat?
اين يه جور درمانه؟
Lie down.
.دراز بکش
What's that?
اون يه؟
A syringe.
.يک سرن
Relax.
.راحت باش
My arm's stinging.
.بازوي من حساسه
It's a tranquilizer.
.اين يه آرام بخشه
What for?
واسه ي؟
These things are all bullshit.
.اين يزا همه ِرته
Ifyou'd trusted psychiatrists more, you mightn't be here now.
اه کمي بيشتر به روانزشک ها اعتماد داشتي .احتمالا الان اينجا نبودي
That finger, it's making me nervous.
اون انشتت .منو عصبي ميکنه
You needn't be afraid.
.لازم نيست بترسي
- I'm not afraid. - Stop talking and concentrate.
.نميترسم - .ساکت باش و تمرکز کن -
Come on.
.زود باش
Fuck.
.اييدم
I feel dizzy.
.احساس يجي مي کنم
Good-bye, Cesar.
.خدافظ سزار
Very good. Now let's see ifyou can tell me about that dream.
خيلي خب، ببينم الان ميتوني در مورد .اون رويا با من حرف بزني
- In my dream, it isn't raining. - The office dream.
.توي روياي من بارون نميومد - .روياي توي اداره -
Eli.
.اِلي
That's it. I want you to tell me who Eli is.
.خودشه، ميخوام بهم بي اِلي کيه
- A secretary. - Eli is a secretary?
.يه منشي - اِلي يه منشيه؟ -
She tells me to go in. They're expecting me.
اون به من فت برو داخل .اونا منتظر من بودن
Who 's expecting you?
کي منتظرت بود؟
- The Frenchman from the TV. - Sit down, please.
.همون مرد فرانسوي توي تلويزيون - .بنشينيد لطفا -
It's a contract.
.اين يه قرارداده
- Eli-- - Cesar, who is Eli?
.اِلي - سزار، اِلي کيه؟ -
You won 't regret it. Sign.
شيمون نخواهي شد .امضا کن
- What are you signing? - Eli will see to everything.
ي رو امضا مي کني؟ - .اِلي همه  يز رو ميبينه -
What have you signed?
ي رو امضا کردي؟
What's wrong?
ه مشکلي يش اومده؟
What's wrong, Cesar?
سزار، ه مشکلي يش اومده؟
Why are you crying?
را ريه مي کني؟
- I'm going to die. - You're not going to die.
.من دارم مي ميرم - .قرار نيست که بميري -
- I don 't know how many. - How many what?
.نميدونم قدر - قدر ي؟ -
- Pills. - You took pills?
.قرص - تو قرص رفتي؟ -
- How many should I take? - Pills to feel better?
قدر بايد بخورم؟ - منظورت قرصه براي بهتر شدن؟ -
I don 't want to.
.من نميخوام
When I count to three, you'll wake up. One. Two.
وقتي تا سه شمردم .تو بيدار ميشي. يک. دو
I thought that, up to now, you'd told me the truth.
تا الان فکر مي کردم .که راستشو به من فتي
What do you mean?
منظورت يه؟
You said you took nothing.
.تو فتي که هيي از اونا نرفتي
Cesar, I'll ask you for the last time.
.سزار، واسه آخرين بار ازت ميرسم
- Did you take drugs? - Fuck! Why does everyone--
تو دارو رفتي؟ - ...لعنت! را همه فکر مي کنن -
Stop playacting. Tell me the truth!
طفره نرو .حقيقت رو به من بو
- I must know what you took. - I didn't take anything!
.بايد بدونم ي رفتي - !من يزي نرفتم -
Don't you see? Your brain could have been affected by the pills.
.نميبيني؟ اون قرص ها روي مغزت تاثير ذاشتن
- I didn't take any! - You said you did!
!خودت فتي که رفتي -
It's just a dream!
.اون فقط يه رويا بوده
Why make it more important than it is?
را اين قضيه رو بزرش مي کني؟
Can't you tell dreams from reality? I can!
تو فرق رويا و واقعيت رو تشخيص مي دي؟ !من مي تونم
Really? Don't make me laugh!
!واقعا؟ منو نخندون بابا
Bodies that come to life, people who disappear...
اجسادي که زنده ميشن .مردمي که ناديد ميشن
you, the Phantom of the Opera!
!و خودت، يک تَوهم در اُرا
Tell me one thing. Do you remember what you did to Sofia?
يه يزو به من بو. يادت مياد که با سوفيا يکار کردي؟
It wasn't Sofia.
.اون سوفيا نبود
I don't care who it was. What did you do to her?
مهم نيست کي بوده با اون يکار کردي؟
You remember?
يادت مياد؟
My God!
!واي خدا جون
What are you doing? I thought you were a burglar.
يکار داري مي کني؟ .من فکر کردم يه دزده
Who are you?
تو کي هستي؟
I'm Sofia.
.من « سوفيا » هستم
Sofia.
.سوفيا
You're not Sofia.
.تو سوفيا نيستي
Cesar, this will all be over soon.
.سزار، همه اينها بزودي تموم ميشه
We'll be together again.
.ما دوباره با هم خواهيم بود
You'll forget Nuria and I won't be afraid ofyou.
تو نوريا رو فراموش خواهي کرد .و من ديه از تو نميترسم
- I'm thirsty. - I'll get some water.
.من تشنه ام - .الان واست آب ميارم -
Sofia!
!سوفيا
Yes, Cesar, I'm Sofia.
.درسته، سزار. من سوفيا هستم
I'm Sofia.
.من سوفيا هستم
I want to see you.
.ميخوام ببينمت
I want to see you!
!ميخوام ببينمت
At times you dream you're with someone.
وقتايي که رويا ميبيني .يه نفر مياد يشت
For example, your father.
.مثلا، درت
In seconds, he becomes your mother...
و در يه ثانيه، اون تبديل ميشه به مادرت
and then, the news vendor on the corner.
و سس يه روزنامه فروش در يه وشه؛...
Yet you still feel as if you're talking to the same person.
ولي هنوز فکر مي کني که با همون .فرد اول داري صحبت مي کني
You thought you were at home, but suddenly you realize you're in a school.
فکر مي کردي که توي خونه هستي، ولي .يهو متوجه ميشي که توي يه مدرسه هستي
Or a hospital, or a prison.
.يا يه بيمارستان، يا يه زندان
Dreams are like that.
.روياها اينطوري هستن
And at times the mind behaves as if it were in a dream.
و هر باز ذهن بونه اي رفتار ميکنه .که با رويا رفتار مي کنه
- You know what derangement is? - For fuck's sake!
ميدوني اين ه اختلاليه؟ - !!دليلش رو اييدمت -
Say I'm stupid ifyou want, but this isn't derangement!
اه دوست داري بو من ديوونه ام !اما اين اختلال نيست
Then what is it?
س يه؟
You tell me, because I don't know.
تو به من بو .ون من نميدونم
I don't know what's in here, or why you killed your girlfriend.
نميدونم اين تو ه خبره .يا اينکه را دوست دخترت رو کشتي
I don't know who Eli is, or that man from the TV.
نميدونم اِلي کيه .يا اون مرد توي تلويزيون رو نمي شناسم
- I don't know anything. - That makes two of us.
.من هيي رو نميدونم - .اينطوري دوتا ميشيم -
Will you still come after the trial?
هنوز هم بعد از محاکمه مياي؟
Don't you hate the sight of me?
از ديدن من متنفر نيستي؟
- What will you plead? - Why do you ask that?
از ي دفاع مي کني؟ - را اينو مي رسي؟ -
The first hearing is next week.
.اولين جلسه محاکمه، هفته بعده
Temporary derangement.
.تظاهر به اختلال رواني موقتا
It's your best chance.
.بهترين شانس توست
Even so, it won't be much use.
.با اين حال هم زياد کاربرد نداره
They won't believe me.
.اونا حرف منو باور نمي کنن
Even I don't believe it.
.حتي من هم باور نمي کنم
What do you believe?
تو به ي اعتقاد داري؟
I thinkyou're very sick and should stay here for a long time.
من فکر مي کنم تو خيلي مريضي و .بايد براي مدت زيادي اينجا بموني
Don't worry. I'll get at least 20 years.
نران نباش .حداقل 20 سال واسم مي برن
Cesar, you may not believe it, but I care about you.
سزار، شايد باورت نشه .اما من بهت اهميت ميدم
I care a lot about you.
.خيلي بهت اهميت ميدم
Look, kid.
.ببين، به
Your case interests me. I'm sorry about what's happened.
من به قضيه تو علاقمند شدم .در مورد اتفاقاتي که افتاده متاسفم
I even thought someone was playing tricks on you, but...
حتي فکر مي کنم کسي تو ...رو به بازي رفته، اما
I can't and mustn't exceed my duties.
اما نميتونم و نبايد از .حد وظيفه ام خارج بشم
- I'm just a psychiatrist. - You don't look like one.
.من فقط يه روانزشکم - .تو مثل يه نفري -
- What do I look like? - My father.
من مثل کي هستم؟ - .مثل درم -
Preaching at me all day.
.تمام روز نصيحتم مي کرد
Your father's dead.
.درت مُرده
There you go.
.ميتوني بري
By the way, what happened to that man with the wife and two daughters?
راستي، ه اتفاقي واسه اون مرد و همسر و دو دخترش افتاد؟
I don't know. I never saw him again.
.نميدونم .ديه هرز نديدمش
Take my advice, get a lawyer.
.يه نصيحت مي کنمت، يه وکيل بير
Good-bye, Cesar.
.خدافظ، سزار
Good-bye.
.خدافظ
...the main Spanish investment, but certainly the most novel.
مهمترين سرمايه ذاري اسانيايي... .و البته جديد ترين نوعشه
...its economic presence in Cuba.
.رخداد اقتصادي اون در کوبا...
...depending on the era.
به دوره بستي داره...
In the Roman Empire, for example, the normal thing was to live...
براي مثال در امراطوري روم .عادي ترين يز، زندي کردن
only 25 years.
.به مدت 25 سال بود
Who's got the remote?
کنترل دست کيه؟
Give it to me!
!بدش به من
Get it off him!
!اونو ازش بير
What's up?
ه خبره؟
There's a computer here connected to Internet.
.اينجا يه رايانه به اينترنت وصله
They'll only let me use it ifyou come with me.
فقط اه تو با من باشي .ميذارن از اون استفاده کنم
- Why do you want Internet? - I know what Eli is.
اينترنت واسه ي مي خواي؟ - من ميدونم اِلي يه؟ -
Wait!
!صبر کن
Eli isn't a person, it's a company.
اِلي انسان نيست .يک شرکته
- How do you know? - It isn't Eli.
از کجا ميدوني؟ - .اون اِلي نيست -
It's L.E. They're the initials of an American company.
هستش (L.E.) اون در اصل اِل-اي .يه شرکت آمريکايي
- What are you doing? - Checking the "initials program."
يکار داري ميکني؟ - .دارم اين حروف اختصاري رو بررسي مي کنم -
It'll tell us all it knows about L.E.
اينطوري همه يز در مورد اِل-اي .رو بدست مياريم
Shit!
.لعنت
- It'll take ages. - No, wait.
.اونا عمر انسان رو مييرن - .نه صبر کن -
Fuck!
!!اييدم
I feel like I've done this before.
.حس مي کنم قبلا اين کارو کردم
A cerebral dysfunction. A lapse in the brain.
.يک عملکرد ناقص ذهني .يک خطا در ذهن
No, not this time.
.نه، اين بار نه
My God!
!خداي من
- That's it. - The photo in your dream?
.خودشه - .تصوير توي روياي تو -
I had to see it before I could dream about it, right?
قبل از ديدن روياش بايد اونو ميديدم، درسته؟
"Cyronics."
.(کريونيک (انجماد
- Cryonization. - I'll print this.
.انجماد سازي - .اينو رينت مي يرم -
Wait a minute. I don't see what this has to do with your case.
يه لحظه صبر کن. نمي فهمم اين .ه ربطي به قضيه تو داره
The key is in here. Look, there's an office in Madrid.
سرنخ همين جاست .ببين، يه دفتر کار توي مادريد هستش
I'll go and check it out.
.من ميرم و اونو بررسي ميکنم
No! I have to go, too.
.نه، منم بايد بيام
- I can't get you out of here. - I'd be let out under supervision.
.من نميتونم تو رو از اينجا بيرون ببرم - .من تحت مراقبت بيرون ميام -
Make up some excuse.
.يه بهانه اي جور کن
- It isn't easy. - You can do it.
.اين آسون نيست - .تو مي توني اينکارو بکني -
You know something else, don't you?
تو يز ديه اي ميدوني، مه نه؟
I don't know anything.
.من هيي نميدونم
- I've just got a feeling. - What is it?
.فقط يه حسي دارم - ه حسي؟ -
I have to go there, one way or another.
.بايد هرطور شده برم اونجا
Let's get things straight. We're outside, I'm armed.
بزار همه يز رو بهت وشزد کنم .ما بيرون مراقبيم، من مسلح هستم
My job is to stop you doing anything stupid.
وظيفه من اينه که نذارم .کار احمقانه اي انجام بدي
Try anything, and you get a bullet.
.اه خطايي بکني، يه لوله ميره توي تنت
I've been here before.
.من قبلا اينجا بودم
- This way. - Move.
.از اين طرف - .حرکت کن -
You've got 20 minutes.
.فقط 20 دقيقه وقت دارين
It's just like in my dream.
.دقيقا مثل رويامه
Good morning. Can I help you?
.صبح بخير مي تونم کمکتون کنم؟
Well, actually, we wanted to speak to Mr. Duvernois.
خب، البته، ما مي خوايم .با آقاي دووِرنوس صحبت کنيم
He's my son.
.اين سر منه
He's very shy.
.خيلي خجالتيه
Mr. Duvernois isn't here right now.
.آقاي دووِرنوس فعلا تشريف ندارن
But, first of all, do you know what cryonization is?
اما، قبل از هريزي، آيا شما ميدونيد که کرايونيزيشن يه؟
Well, more or less.
.خب، کَمابيش
Here are some leaflets. You can read them while you're waiting.
اينجا ند تا کاتالو است .ميتونين تا وقتي که منتظرين، اونا رو مطالعه کنيد
One of my colleagues will be with you soon.
.يکي از همکارام بزودي ميان خدمتتون
Thankyou.
.مکرم
"Live without limits. Tomorrow is for the foresighted."
زندي بدن محدوديت" ."فردا براي عاقبت انديشي است
What is this? Some kind of sect?
اين يه؟ يه نوع فرقه است؟
"Cryonization is the biostasis or preservation of human beings.
کرايونيزيشن، حالت سکون و نيز " .راه بقاي نسل بشر است
It is the bridge to carry our patients to a future...
آن لي است براي عبور .بيماران به آينده
when technology will restore them to life."
تا زماني که تکنولوژي بتونه .اونا رو به زندي برردونه
You pay to live eternally.
.شما هزينه مي کنيد تا زندي ابدي داشته باشين
They laughed at Jules Verne.
.اونها ژول ورن رو مسخره کردن
Cesar, all this is absolutely impossible.
.سزار، همه اينها غير ممکنه
What do you know of the future?
تو در مورد آينده ي ميدوني؟
They promise what the Church has always promised.
اونها يزي رو قول ميدن که .هميشه کشيش قول ميداده
Immortality. Except they're quacks, not priests.
فنا ناذيري .فرق اونا اينه که کشيش نيستن
How are you involved?
خب، اين به تو ه ارتباطي داره؟
You're not cryonized. You're alive.
تو که منجمد (کرايونايز) نشدي .تو زنده اي
This is the contract, ifyou want to look at it.
اين فرم قرارداده .اه مي خواي ببينيش
The procedure is very simple. You could die at any time.
روند کار خيلي ساده است .تو هر زمان بخواي مي توني بميري
Today, tomorrow, in 20 years. It doesn't matter to us.
امروز، فردا، 20 سال ديه .براي ما فرقي نميکنه
At the very moment you're declared legally dead...
از لحظه اي که اظهارنامه .مرت قانونا صادر بشه
Life Extension transfers your body to our store in Arizona.
سازمان " تمديد عمر" بدن شما رو .به انبار ما در آريزونا انتقال ميده
There, it's frozen at minus 78 degrees.
در اونجا در دماي منفي 78 .درجه نهداري ميشه
We call that "total suspension," and it costs $240,000.
"ما به اون مييم " سکون کامل .که البته 240000 دلار هزينه داره
30,000 pays for the freezing process, and the rest...
مبلغ 30000 دلار بابت فرايند انجماد .و الباقي آن
goes into an investment fund...
.در يه حساب ذخيره ميشه
the interests from which pay for maintenance...
...و از سود اون صرف تامين هزينه نهداري و
and resurrection costs, the day that it's possible.
.در صورت امکان صرف هزينه تجديد حيات خواهد شد
If it is possible.
.اه ممکن باشه
We believe that the reanimation of the dead will be possible.
.ما معتقديم که تجديد حيات مرده امکان ذيره
- What's this? - What?
اين يه؟ - ي؟ -
Clause 1 4. Artificial perception.
بند 14 .ادراک مصنوعي
It's a concept that we haven't fully developed yet.
.اون يه  مفهوميه که ما هنوز توسعه نداديمش
Look. This is a life.
.ببين. اين زنديه
Birth and death.
.تولد و مر
Let's say you've got a terminal illness.
تصور کنيد که به يه بيماري .لا علاج مبتلا شدين
Of course you want to go on living, but not in the future.
البته شما دوست دارين که زندي کنيد .اما نه در آينده
That doesn't interest you. You want to live your life now.
شما علاقه اي به اين کار ندارين .شما زندي عادي رو مي سندين
Very well. You die, we freeze you...
بسيار خب .شما مي ميريد و ما شما رو منجمد مي کنيم
and when we can resuscitate you, we'll have you live...
وقتي تونستيم مجددا شما رو زنده کنيم .شما رو قادر ميسازيم که يه زندي خيالي
a dream.
.داشته باشين
- A dream? - It will all look real.
يه رويا؟ - .کاملا شبيه روياست -
Your family and friends, your city...
شما و دوستانتان ...شهر شما
the world, even this office.
.اين دنيا، حتي اين دفتر کار
But it'll be a virtual reality.
.اما اون يه واقعيت مجازي خواهد بود
What's more, we'll make you forget that you've died...
علاوه بر اون، کاري مي کنيم که فراموش کنيد .قبلا مرديد
and that you signed this contract.
.و اينکه اين قرارداد رو امضا کردين
- How? - Very simple.
طور؟ - .خيلي ساده -
Wiping it from your memory.
.از روي حافظتون اکش مي کنيم
You'll live your life linearly, as if nothing had happened.
شما زنديتون رو ادامه ميدين .انار که اتفاقي نيفتاده
And best of all, you'll live it as you like, as you wish.
و بهتر از همه اينکه، اونطور که .علاقه دارين، زندي مي کنيد
You'll decide at all times.
.هميشه شما تصميم يرنده هستين
But what ifthere were mistakes?
اه اشتباهي يش بياد ي ميشه؟
What if the dream was transformed into a nightmare?
اه رويا به يه کابوس تبديل بشه ي؟
Well, the subconscious can always play a dirty trick.
خب، قسمت نيمه هوشيار ذهن هميشه .ميتونه يه کلکي سوار کنه
But we're not cowboys. This is a serious company.
اما ما که او رون نيستيم اينجا يه شرکت جدي هستش
And virtual reality technology is constantly making huge advances.
و فناوري واقعيت مجازي همواره .در حال توسعه است
Look.
.ببين
I'll be honest.
.بايد روراست باشم
Signing Clause 1 4 is like signing for paradise.
امضاي بند 14 مثل .امضاي ورودي به بهشته
It's hard to believe. But they laughed at Jules Verne.
باورش سخته .اما اونها هم ژول ورن رو مسخره کردن
Excuse me.
.ببخشين
- Where are you going so fast? - To the bathroom.
کجا دارين با اين عجله ميرين؟ - .دستشويي -
- Well, not so fast. - I'll go with him.
.باشه، ولي نه با اين عجله - .من با اون ميرم -
He just felt ill, don't worry.
.يهو حالش بد شد، نران نباش
Cesar, calm down, please.
.سزار لطفا آروم باش
This is a dream. It's the only explanation.
.اين يه روياست .تنها توضيحش همينه
What he said is impossible.
.يزي که اون فت، غير ممکنه
In the 20th century, but maybe not in the 30th.
حد اقل واسه قرن 20 ممکن نيست .شايد قرن 30 عملي باشه
- Maybe not, but we're in 1 997. - That's what it seems.
شايد نه، ولي ما توي سال 1997 هستيم .اينطوري به نظر ميرسه
- I paid for it to seem like that. - Listen! If this is a dream--
من ول دادم که اينطوري تصور کنم - ...وش کن، اه اين يه رويا باشه -
Look at me! If this is a dream, it means that I don't exist!
به من ناه کن! اه اين يه رويا باشه .س يعني من وجود ندارم
- I just imagine you. - No!
.من فقط تو رو خيال کردم - !نه -
- Cesar, I'm real. - How do I know that?
.سزار، من واقعي هستم - از کجا اينو مي دونم؟ -
Can't you tell a dream from reality? Is this a dream, eh?
مه فرق رويا و واقعيت رو نميدوني؟ به نظرت اين يه روياست، ها؟
Tell me, is this a dream?
بو ديه، اين يه روياست؟
Cesar, I'm wearing myself out over this case.
.سزار، من ديه از اين رونده خسته شدم
There is no case. I didn't kill anyone. It's all a nightmare.
رونده اي وجود نداره. من کسي رو نکشتم .اون فقط يه کابوس بوده
Fuck it, Cesar, trust me! This isn't a dream.
ريدم بهش! سزار، به من اعتماد کن .اين يه رويا نيست
- They got it wrong. - Who?
.اونا اشتباه رفتن - کي؟ -
I don't know! But they mixed up Sofia and Nuria! I see a face that isn't mine.
نميدونم! اما اونها سوفيا و نوريا رو قاطي کردن .من يه هره مي بينم که به من تعلق نداره
I'm sick of hearing that! Your face is fine.
از شنيدن اون حالم به هم مي خوره .صورتت خوبه
You're behaving like a child, hiding behind that mask.
با مخفي شدن شت اون نقاب .مثل يه به عمل مي کني
- Go on, take it off! - I don't want to see myself!
!زود باش، در بيارش - !من نمي خوام خودم رو ببينم -
I don't care about that. I want to see you.
.واسم مهم نيست .من مي خوام ببينمت
Don't you realize? All that matters is what I see! It's my dream!
نمي فهمي، هر يزي !که مي بينم، روياي من است
Say that once more and I'll have you locked up in an asylum.
اه يه بار ديه اين حرف رو بزني .توي يه تيمارستان محبوست مي کنم
Show me your face. Now. You owe it to me.
صورتت رو به من نشون بده .الان. تو به من مديوني
Cesar, look in the mirror and tell me ifyou thinkyou're disfigured.
سزار توي آينه ناه کن  و به من بو .که آيا صورتت داغونه
God!
!خدايـــــا
Why do you keep seeing what isn't there?
را به يزي که اونجا نيست فکر مي کني؟
- You look fine. - I'm a monster!
.تو مشکلي نداري - !!مثل يه هيولا شدم -
What do you mean? Anybody'd like to have your face.
منظورت يه؟ - .هر کسي دوست داره هره تو رو داشته باشه -
You look normal.
.تو عادي هستي
Not just normal. You're handsome!
.نه فقط عادي !حتي خوش قيافه هم هستي
Cesar, listen. Maybe you've got something like anorexia.
سزار، وش کن. شايد تو به يه يزي .شبيه به بي اشتهايي مبتلا شدي
Some girls insist they're fat and end up crazy.
بعضي دخترها اصرار دارن که اق هستن .و در نهايت ديوونه ميشن
Cesar!
!سزار
I want to wake up!
!ميخوام بيدار بشم
- Hold it! - I want to wake up!
!صبر کن - !ميخوام بيدار بشم -
Fuck!
!!اييدم
Shit!
!لعنتي
- Freeze! - Don't shoot!
!حرکت نکنيد - !شليک نکن -
This is a nightmare! It's a nightmare!
!اين يه کابوسه
You! Wait a minute! You're not to leave!
!تو! يه لحظه صبر کن .تو نبايد بري
Stop!
!ايست
Wait a minute!
!يه لحظه وايسا
It's a dream!
!اين يه روياست
Don't move! Drop the gun!
!حرکت نکن! اسلحه رو بنداز
- I want to wake up. I want to wake up. - Don't move!
.ميخوام بيدار بشم، ميخوام بيدار بشم - !حرکت نکن -
I want to wake up!
!ميخوام بيدار بشم
Antonio.
.آنتونيو
Antonio!
!آنتونيو
What?
يه؟
You're crushing me.
.تو منو له کردي
I'd better not move. I've been shot in the back.
بهتره حرکت نکنم .از شت بهم شليک شده
How do you know?
از کجا مي دوني؟
Well...
...خب
because--
...ون
What's going on here?
اينجا ه خبره؟
What the fuck's going on?
اين ديه ه ُه کاريه؟
I told you, it's a dream.
.بهت که فتم، اين يه روياست
Shut up! Shut up!
!خفه شو! خفه شو
I know what this is. It's one of those Candid Camera jokes.
من مي دونم اين يه .اين يه جور دوربين مخفيه
You did a great job, I loved it, but enough's enough!
کارتون خوب بود، خوشم اومد .ولي ديه کافيه
- I see someone. - Where?
.يکي رو ديدم - کجا؟ -
Up there, on the roof.
.اون بالا، روي سقف
I can't see a thing.
.من يزي نمي بينم
Where are you going?
کجا داري ميري؟
Come on, Antonio. Don't think about it anymore oryou'll go crazy.
بيا آنتونيو، ديه در موردش .فکر نکن ور نه ديوونه ميشي
Hello, Cesar.
.سلام، سزار
It's time I introduced myself.
.الان وقتشه خودم رو معرفي کنم
My name is Serge Duvernois. I represent Life Extension.
من سرج دووِرنوس هستم .من نظريه تمديد عمر را ارائه کردم
We met...
...ملاقات ما
1 50 years ago.
.حدود 150 سال يش بوده
What? Has the world gone mad?
ي؟ دنيا قاطي کرده؟
There's no world. It's all in that gentleman's mind.
دنيايي وجود نداره همه يز توي ذهن اين مرده
Including you and me.
.و همينطور تو و من
Sure! Shall I thump you to see if it hurts?
البته! ميشه يه مشت بهت بزنم ببينم درد ميکنه يا نه؟
Try it. They can make you disappear right now, like everyone else.
امتحان کن! اونا ميتونن کاري کنن که .همين الان ناديد بشي، درست مثل بقيه
- And who are "they," may I ask? - The company.
ميشه برسم منظورت از "اونها" کيه؟ - .شرکت -
Life Extension.
.تمديد عمر
They know everything we're saying.
اونا از هر يزي که حرف ميزنيم .خبر دارن
They know what is going through Cesar's mind an instant after he thinks it.
به محض اينکه سزار به يزي فکر کنه .اونا ازش مطلع ميشن
If they can make me disappear, why haven't they done it?
اه ميتونن منو ناديد کنن س را اين کارو نکردن؟
It would be virtually incorrect.
.از لحاظ مجازي کار درستي نيست
You've just saved his life.
.تو همين حالا جونش رو نجات دادي
Virtually incorrect? Do you think I'm an idiot or what?
از لحاظ مجازي غلطه؟ شما فکر مي کنيد من احمقم؟
No, quite the opposite. You're a great guy.
نه، دقيقا برعکس .تو يه مرد عالي هستي
A character who is very necessary for Cesar.
.يه شخصيت که براي سزار خيلي مفيده
A character?
يه شخصيت؟
- Where are you going? - To look for someone.
کجا داري ميري؟ - .ميرم يه نفرو ببينم -
There is no one. People aren't necessary now.
هيکس نيست .الان وجود مردم ضرورتي نداره
Why didn't you wake me before?
را قبلا منو بيدار نکردي؟
You only had to ask. But that was difficult.
تو فقط بايد درخواست مي کردي .اما اين مشکل بود
Because, in theory, you wouldn't know you were dreaming.
ون به طور تئوريک تو نمي دونستي .که داري رويا ميبيني
Since when?
از ه زماني؟
Remember the day of the discotheque?
اون شب توي کلو شبانه رو به ياد مياري؟
That night, when you fell asleep on the sidewalk...
...شبي که کنار خيابون خوابت بُرد
was the one chosen for the splice.
.شب انتخابي براي اين يوند بود
What splice?
ه يوندي؟
The splice between your real life andyour virtual life.
.يوند زندي واقعي تو با زندي مجازي ات
A splice of 1 50 years which you didn 't notice...
يوند ميان 150 سال ...که تو اصلا متوجه اون نشدي ون
because you were dead and frozen.
.تو مرده و منجمد شده بودي
From when you woke up...
.از لحظه اي که بيدار شدي
nothing was real.
.هي يز واقعي نبوده
We wiped what really happened from your memory.
ما اون يزي که واقعا در ذهنت .اتفاق افتاده رو اک کرديم
What was it?
اون ي بوده؟
You never saw Sofia again.
.تو ديه هرز سوفيا رو نديدي
And the doctors were never able to rebuild your face.
و اينکه دکترها هرز نميتونن .هره تو رو درست کنن
You woke up on that street with an awful hangover.
تو کنار اون خيابون .به شکل يه الکلي ترسناک بيدار شدي
You shutyourselfaway for months.
تو خودتو براي ند ماه حبس کرده بودي
One dayyou learned that we existed.
يه روز به اين ميرسي که .ما براي هم بوديم
You came to the office, you signed the contract...
اومدي به دفتر من ...قرارداد رو امضا کردي
and then...
...و سس
you killedyourself.
.خودت رو کشتي
I paid for this?
براي اين ول دادم؟
I paid for Nuria to come back as Sofia?
من ول دادم که نوريا به جاي سوفيا بياد يش من؟
I paid to look like a monster again?
من ول دادم که دوباره مثل يه هيولا باشم؟
I paid to live this nightmare?
من واسه اين کابوس ول دادم؟
You paid to live whatever you wanted.
تو ول دادي که هر جور .دلت خواست زندي کني
We just provided the setting and the characters.
.ما فقط مکان و شخصيت ها رو ايجاد کرديم
You invented your hell.
.تو جهنم خودت رو ايجاد کردي
I tried to warn you in that bar.
توي اون مشروب فروشي .بهت هشدار دادم
I said it all depended on your mind.
.فتم که به ذهن خودت بستي داره
Do I just have to want it?
آيا من بايد همينطور بخوام؟
- Can Antonio come-- - There's no one here.
ميشه آنتونيو بياد؟ - .هيکس اينجا نيست -
They can't have made 4 million people disappear!
اونا نميتونن 4 ميليون نفر !رو ناديد کنن
You've overcome your fears.
.تو به ترست غلبه کردي
Ifyou want, we can try again...
.اه بخواي، ما ميتونيم از نو شروع کنيم
have you live a wonderful dream...
.تا دوباره يه روياي عالي داشته باشي
with money, friends, Sofia, or whatever girl you want.
به همراه ثروت، دوستان، سوفيا .يا هر دختري که دوست داشته باشي
You just have to ask.
.فقط بايد بخواي
I don't want more dreams.
.من ديه رويا نمي خوام
It isn't a dream!
!اين يه رويا نيست
Cesar, listen to me.
.سزار، ببين ي ميم
This is real. This man is a sham.
.اين واقعيه .اين مرد ساختيه
Let's go down and look for people.
.بريم ايين و مردم رو ببين
Ignore him. It's logical for him to behave like this...
بهش توجه نکن، اين رفتار ...براي اون منطقيه
but he doesn't feel anything.
.اما اون هي يز رو حس نمي کنه
I don't feel anything?
من يزي رو حس نمي کنم؟
What do you know about what I feel?
تو از يزي که من حس مي کنم، ي مي دوني؟
Ignore him, he isn't real.
.بهش توجه نکن، اون واقعي نيست
Yes, I am real!
.البته که واقعي ام
I've got a wife and two daughters.
.من يه همسر و دو دختر دارم
His personality is designed so that he'll say all this now.
شخصيت اون طراحي شده؛ .به همين دليل اين حرفا رو ميزنه
Where are my daughters? God!
دختراي من کجا هستن؟ !خداي من
Cesar, we can offeryou another possibility.
.سزار ميتونه بهت يه فرصت ديه بده
In 1 997, it was impossible to rebuild your face.
در سال 1977، ترميم .هره تو ممکن نبود
But out there, it's the year 2 1 45.
.اما اون بيرون الا سال 2145 هستش
You wouldn't believe the things surgery can do.
باورت نميشه جراحان ه کارايي .ميتونن انجام بدن
You could wake up...
...ميتوني بيدار شي
and live in the future like a normal person.
و در دنياي آينده مثل يه شخصيت .عادي به زندي ادامه بدي
- In the future? - You have to choose.
در آينده؟ - .بايد انتخاب کني -
How could I wake up?
طور مي تونم بيدار بشم؟
How would you wake from your worst nightmare?
از بدترين کابوست طور ميتوني بيدار شي؟
No, Cesar, don't listen to him!
.نه، سزار. به حرفاش وش نده
Your partners set this up! They want you to kill yourself!
!شرکات اين نقشه رو ريختن !اونا مي خوان تا خودت رو بکشي
He's done that. Now it'll just be a formality.
.اون قبلا اين کارو کرده .الان فقط يه طورايي فرماليته (نمايشي) است
- I'm going to do it. - Very well.
.اين کارو مي کنم - .بسيار خب -
Do you have any wish before you die?
آيا قبل از مرت، آرزويي نداري؟
Let them out there read my mind.
.بذارين اون افراد بيرون ذهن منو بخونن
Who are you?
تو کي هستي؟
I don't know.
.نمي دونم
Don't keep suffering. It's all in your head.
ديه به خودت سختي نده .اينا همه توي ذهنته
It's all psychological.
.همه اش مسائل روانيه
Come on, Cesar.
.بيا، سزار
- What will happen to them? - Don't prolong this farewell.
واسه اينا ه اتفاقي ميفته؟ - .اين خداحافظي رو طولاني تر نکنش -
You think they're your friends, but they're just images.
تو فکر مي کني که اونا دوستانت هستن .اما اونا فقط يه تصوير خيالي هستن
That man isn't really crying.
.اين مرد واقعا ريه نمي کنه
- I forgot, I get vertigo. - Then don't look.
.يادم نبود که از بلندي ميترسم - .س ناه نکن -
Good-bye, Cesar.
.بدرود سزار
Relax.
.آروم باش
Open your eyes.
.شماتو باز کن